字幕来源：第三楼字幕网
我相信美满结局
I believe in happy endings.
而且这是对我来说唯一有意义的事
And it's the only thing that's ever made sense to me.
你知道 我以前常常会把自己 锁在房间里
You know, I used to lock myself in my room
用广播听着所有那些老歌
and watch all the oldies on PBS.
我们付不起有线电视费
We couldn't afford cable, which was fine.
你知道 就是那种少女怀孕时
You know, who needs to watch shows on teenage pregnancy
屋子里还有其他孩子在相互吵闹时 看的那种电视
and kids living in the same house screaming at each other?
在我家那个地方 这被称之为"星期三"
In my neighborhood, that was called wednesday.
那个 我以前还和斯宾塞·屈塞 凯特·赫伯恩一起逃跑过
Well, I used to escape with Spencer Tracy and Kate Hepburn
还和弗雷德·阿斯泰尔 金吉·罗杰斯在舞池旋转过
and Fred Astaire spinning Ginger Rogers on the dance floor
最后撞上了劳伦·白考尔
and Bogie finally plant one on Lauren Bacall.
她当时穿着华丽的黑白的裙子
All in glorious black and white.
你喜欢通话?
You like fairy tales?
我觉得我们是不是都需要一点魔力 你不觉得吗?
I think we all need a little magic from time to time, don't you think?
我是说 如果默夫云·莱罗依
I mean, what would Lana Turner have done
从来没去过好莱坞和藤街的
if Mervyn Leroy had never gone into Schwab's
嘉信餐厅
on Hollywood and Vine
看到拉娜·特纳在那喝可乐 她会怎么样呢?
and he saw her there, drinking that coke.
她当时就在那 而那瓶可乐 改变了她的人生
She was discovered right there, and that coke changed her life.
好吧 于是他们告诉游客
Well, so they tell the tourists,
因为那不是嘉信餐厅
because it wasn't Schwab's
事实上那是在日落大道和 卡登大道交汇处的大礼貌餐厅
It was actually a place called top hat on Sunset and McCadden.
而且主人公也不是默夫云·莱罗依
And it wasn't Mervyn Leroy,
事实上是好莱坞的一个记者
it was actually a guy from the Hollywood Reporter.
而且她的名字甚至也不叫拉娜·特纳
And her name wasn't even Lana Turner then.
而是朱迪 事实上 她的真名叫茱莉亚
It was Judy... Actually her real name was Julia.
但这些你全都知道 对吗?
But you knew all that, right?
你知道 尽管这魔力可能不太一样
You know, it doesn't really have the same magic, though.
片名：爱你就捧你
这么说你觉得你会来到这 是因为魔力?
So you think you got here by magic?
这是最纯粹的说法
In its purest form.
我是说 人生中有一千次...
I mean, there are a thousand, no...
不 是一百万次的左右抉择
There are a million lefts or rights.
选择一条路 而不是逃避
Picking up instead of dodging a call.
决定去印度而不是意大利
Deciding on indian instead of italian.
你知道 当你只想睡的时候 强迫自己走出去
You know, willing yourself to go out, when all you want to do is sleep.
我甚至能回溯到我踏出的第一步
I can almost trace it back to the very first step.
像拉娜一样
Blows my mind...
为一个可能改变人生的机会的幻想 而欣喜若狂
To think that just like Lana, a chance encounter changed my life.
当然 我一直觉得能改变我人生的
Of course, I always thought the guy who would change my life
会是像马龙·白兰度那样强大的人
would be powerful like Marlon Brando
或是像加里·格兰特那样闪耀的
or sparkle like Cary Grant
或是想詹姆斯·迪恩那样 穿着皮革的人
or smell like worn leather like James Dean.
艾伯森先生 还有什么 需要我帮忙的吗?
Mr. Albertson, do you need me for anything else?
-不用 我可以的 谢谢 -好的
-I'm good. Fine. Thank you. -Okay.
你永远不会想到是一个人
You never think it will just be some guy
就一个看起来普普通通
who looks like some guy
和我们所有其他人一样平凡的人
who's just as screwed up as the rest of us.
你好 我想我预定了房间 德里克·托马斯
Hello. I think I've a reservation. Derek Thomas.
是的 托马斯先生 你的房间是 1369号套房
Yes, Mr. Thomas. You're in suite 1369.
-好的 -行李员
-Okay. -Bellman.
-谢谢 -不客气 这边请
-Thank you. -Sure. Right this way.
-您从哪飞过来的?  -洛杉矶
-Where'd you fly in from? -Los Angeles.
洛杉矶 我一直都想去那
L.A. I've always wanted to go there.
那边美女如云
A lot of pretty girls.
当然 美女到处都是
Of course, there are a lot of pretty girls everywhere.
这是这个世界上的妙处之一
That's one of the nice things about the world.
先生 你以前在我们这住过吗?
So have you stayed with us before, sir?
住过
Yeah.
那边现在的天气如何?
So, how's the weather out there now?
你知道 总是非常的压抑
You know, it's always oppressively perfect.
好吧 看看是谁来了!
Well, look who's here!
赛斯 亲爱的 我以为你住在皮埃尔
Seth, my darling. I thought you were staying at the Pierre.
我还以为你住在丈母娘家呢
And I thought you were at your in-laws.
没有 等明天德尔塔和孩子们到了 我才去那住
No, not till tomorrow. That's when Delta and the kids arrive.
我一个人应付不了她父母
I can't handle her parents by myself.
-人类最好的朋友 -这是威尔巴
-Man's best friend. -This is Wilba.
你待会儿准备去干嘛? 吃晚饭吗?
So what are you doing later? You want some dinner?
不吃了 我好累 精疲力尽
No, I'm so worn out. Exhausted.
你知道 还在倒时差
You know, jet lag and everything.
听听我的不幸遭遇吧
It was a very tough little picture.
没睡觉 背部还受伤了
No sleep. Hurt my back.
我最好洗个盐浴 直接就睡了
I better just take an epsom salt bath and go straight to bed.
晚安 咱们排练时见
Goodnight. I will see you at Rehearsals.
你为什么也下来了?
And why are you getting off?
我住这层啊 1317号房
I'm on this floor. 1317.
真方便 好吧
That's convenient. Okay.
我去睡觉了
I'm going to turn in.
好吧 知道我的导演就在附近 可真令我感到安慰
Well, it's comforting to know my director's close by.
-跟德尔塔问个好 -好的
-Love to Delta. -Okay.
演员啊...
Actors...
是啊 我明白你的意思 我也是个演员!
Yeah, I know what you mean. I'm an actor!
他们总是有些特别之处的 不是吗?
There's something special about them, isn't there?
我就是这意思
That's just what I meant.
干嘛? 我们什么都不想买 所以得了吧!
What? We don't want to buy anything so forget it!
我是和我父母在布鲁克林长大的
I was raised in Brooklyn with my parents,
你知道 那的生活很艰辛
which was tough, you know.
他们很久以前就已经不相信 有什么美满结局了
They stopped believing in happy endings a long time ago.
闭嘴! 我能处理
Shut up! I can handle this.
不! 你才闭嘴
No! You shut up.
但我在努力不去责怪他们
But I try not to blame them.
他们一开始其实挺顺利的
Things started out great for them,
1974年 我妈妈加冕科尼岛小姐
like ma was crowned miss Coney Island, 1974,
全都是因为爸爸
All because of pops.
他是评委中的一员吗?
He was one of the judges?
不 他当时在街上卖热狗的
No. He was selling the hot-dogs on the boardwalk,
但他观看了整场走秀 而且他看见了我妈妈
but he watched the entire pageant, and he sees my ma,
然后就爱上了她 非常
And he falls for her, like, hard.
所以 他就开始往热狗里 加发霉的芥末
So he starts putting all this rotten mustard in all the hot-dogs
而我妈妈是舞台上 唯一一个没跑去厕所
and my ma is the only one who doesn't run off the stage
释放她肚子的人 所以...
clutching her stomach, so...
就搞定了
That sealed it.
他的主意可多了
But he had a million ideas
而且他以前对我妈妈承诺说 他成就大事业
and he used to promise my ma that it was only gonna be a matter of time
只是个时间问题
before one of them hit.
所以 她在一家豪华沙龙里 找了一份洗头发的工作
So she got a job washing hair in a beauty salon
然后她等啊等...
and she was waiting and waiting...
你知道 20年过去了 她还在给人洗头
And you know, twenty years go by and she's still washing hair.
那你父亲做什么呢?
What does he do, your father?
他搞发明
He invents things.
比如?
Like what?
你知道固体胶吗?
Do you know the glue stick?
他发明的?
He invented that?
不 他发明了固体黄油
No. He invented the butter stick,
所以 你可以很方便地 用它涂抹你的吐司
so you smooth it on your toast real good.
但...我是说 那在日本很受欢迎
But... I mean, it was huge in Japan.
你好 薇琪公司
Hello, Vickie's.
嗨 薇琪 我现在在巴克利酒店
Hi, Vickie. I'm over at the Barclay
我打电话是想问今晚
and I was calling about the availability
你们的一个陪同人员是否有空
of one of your escorts for this evening.
先生 您指哪一个?
Which one is that, sir?
就这个网页上的 戈尔
From the webpage here. Glo.
抱歉 能麻烦你稍等一下吗?
Can you hold on just one minute? I'm sorry.
好的
Yeah, okay.
-喂?  -·艾伯森先生
-Hello? -Mr. Albertson.
谁啊 哪位?
Who's this? Who is it?
是我啊 爸爸 我是大卫
It's me, dad. It's David.
大卫 你在哪啊?
David. Where are you?
老天 在家啊 不然你以为我在哪
Home. Geez, dad, where do you think I am?
我们现在准备出发了
We're getting ready to leave.
你要出发了? 我以为你们明天才能到
You're leaving? I thought you guys weren't arriving until tomorrow.
是啊 爸爸 我们准备去吃晚饭了
Yeah, dad, we're just going to dinner.
好吧 大卫 帮个忙 让你妈妈接电话
Okay. David, do me a favor and put your mom on.
妈妈? 我以为妈妈和你在一起呢
Mom? I thought mom was with you.
-什么?  -我开玩笑的 爸爸
-What? -I'm kidding, dad.
-稍等 -等等 大卫
-Just a minute. -Hold it, David.
抱歉 薇琪 再等一下
I'm sorry, just one more minute, Vickie.
你知道 我真的不能再等了
You know, I really can't.
不如我去看看戈尔能不能等吧?
Why don't I see if Glo can do it?
太好了 好! 那个 看看她
Great. Yeah! That, that and, and see if she
是否能在一小时内过来
can maybe come in the next hour or so.
只要我能联系上她 我待会回给你 你在几号房?
If I can reach her. I'll call you back. What room are you in?
1369 名字叫德里克·托马斯
1369. The name's Derek Thomas.
谢谢
Thank you.
-嘿 大卫 -不 我是乔丝
-Hey, David. -No, it's Josie.
爸爸 我等你很久了诶
And I'm kinda tired of waiting, dad.
对不起 乔丝
I'm sorry, Josie.
-等等 等等 我知道 稍等 -爸爸!
Hold on. Hold it. I know. Hold it. Dad!
-你好?  -嗨 阿诺德
-Hello? -Hi, Arnold.
我只是想跟你确认一下明天的时间...
I just wanted to confirm the time for tomorrow...
不 不 赛斯 不是明天
No, no, Seth. It's not tomorrow.
是后天 下午
It's the day after tomorrow. At noon.
-在贝拉斯科?  -对
-At the belasco? -That's right.
-好 晚安 -晚安
-Okay. Good night. -Good night.
很抱歉 乔丝
Sorry about that, Josie.
嘿 不 是我
Hey, no, it's me.
德尔塔 你好吗?
Delta, how are you?
德尔塔 抱歉 是客房服务的 稍等一下
Delta, I'm sorry, it's room service. Just a second.
-喂?  -喂 哪位?
-Hello? -Hello, who's this?
-我是阿诺德 -阿诺德?
-This is Arnold. -Arnold?
我是说 我是德里克 你是薇琪吗?
I mean, this is Derek. Vickie?
是的 那你为什么说是阿诺德?
Yes. Why did you say Arnold?
我没...你知道 因为他们...
I didn't... You know, just 'cause they...
德里克 阿诺德 听起来很像
Derek, Arnold, they sound alike.
就连字母数都一样
Or almost same amount of letters.
什么?
What?
你知道 就像"我的印度名字"的 笑话一样
You know, like a joke. Like it's my indian name.
-你是印度人吗?  -名誉上是
-Are you indian? -Honorary.
你能稍等一下吗?
Can you hold for just a minute?
不 你知道 我只是想及时通知你
No, you know what, I'm just keeping you posted.
戈尔的电话占线了 我会继续打 待会回电话给你
Glo's phone is busy. I'll keep trying. I'll call you back.
好 好 继续打 好
Good. Good. Keep trying. Okay.
德尔塔 抱歉 你好吗?
Delta, I'm sorry. How are you?
很好啊 你在跟谁说话呢?
Fine. Who were you talking to?
就是客房服务 我的背快疼死了
Just room service. My back has been killing me.
你好吗?
But how are you?
我有点紧张 我不敢相信
I'm a little nervous. I can't believe it's been seven years
自打我上台已经7年了 我觉得我今晚可能会睡不着了
since I've been on a stage. I don't think I can sleep tonight.
我也是 我也是
Me too. Me too.
我准备去洗个澡 就直接睡了
I'm just going to take a bath and head straight to bed.
我去接
I'll get it.
反正也总是找你的
It's always for you anyway.
喂? 嗨 薇琪
Hello? Hi, Vickie.
谁啊?
Who is it?
妈妈 是我的老板
It's my boss, mom.
他们就不能别再烦你了吗?
Can't they never leave you alone?
我这是在谋生 好吗?
I'm trying to earn a living, okay?
嗨 薇琪 怎么了?
Hi, Vickie, what's up?
你什么时候能到曼哈顿?
When can you get to Manhattan?
一小时 给我一小时吧
Maybe an hour. Give me an hour.
好极了 有笔吗?
Great. You got a pencil?
-名字叫德里克  D-E-R... -我知道怎么拼
-Here's the name. Derek. D-E-R... -I can spell it.
好吧 姓托马斯 1369号房
Okay. Thomas, room 1369.
好吧 明白 你刚说在哪来着?
Okay, got it. Where'd you say?
-巴克利酒店 -行
-The Barclay. -Done.
这么说传言是真的?
So the rumors are true?
-你的确做过... -缪斯?
-You really did work as a... -A muse?
什么?
A what?
缪斯
A muse.
这是真正的工作吗?
That's a real job?
是啊 对我来说是
Yeah. It was for me.
我的客户大都是些可怜人
My clients were mostly poor souls.
魔力完全被掏空了的人
Completely empty of magic.
所以 我的工作就是让他们重获新生
So it was my job to breathe life back into them.
-看!  -你得让一个人感觉特别
-Look! -You make a person feel special.
把他们当做是这个世界上 最重要的人来对待
You treat them like they're the most important thing in the world.
有那么一小时...
And for an hour...
他们的确是
They are.
有一个特别的客户
There was one particular client which...
我待会再跟你细说他的事吧
I'll tell you more about him in a minute.
他雇了一个私家侦探 让他偷偷跟着我
He hired a private eye, called him a gumshoe, to follow me.
我不介意
I didn't mind.
有人总是想知道我在哪 我觉得
It was kind of flattering that someone wanted to know
这算是对我的奉承
where I was all the time.
好了 稍等
Okay. Hold it.
哪位?
Who is it?
是我 戈尔
It's me. It's Glo.
-嗨 你好 -嗨 你好吗?
-Hi. Hello. -Hi, how are you?
很好 戈尔 对吗?
Good. Glo, right?
是啊 没错 但是衣服换了
Yeah. That's right, but don't wear it out.
我能用下你的卫生间吗?
Say, can I use your bathroom?
当然 就在那边
Yeah. It's right, it's right over there.
-喂?  -德里克? 她已经到了吗?
-Hello? -Derek? Is she there yet?
是的 她现在在卫生间
Yeah, she's in the bathroom.
但是 请稍等
But, hold on.
戈尔 抱歉 是薇琪的电话
Glo, I'm sorry. It's Vickie.
好 告诉她我马上好
Yeah... Tell her I'll be right there.
薇琪 她马上...就来
Vickie, she'll be right there... Here.
她来了 好
Here she is. Okay.
-嗨 -你为什么没打电话来?
-Hi. -Why didn't you call?
我得挂了 我没事 一小时后给你电话
I had to go. I'm fine. I'll call you in an hour.
你知道 可能不止一小时
You know, it could be more than an hour.
他说可能不止一小时
He says it could be more than an hour.
那就让他先付你两小时的钱 待会儿再看
Well, then have him pay you now for two hours, and see how it goes.
好的
Okay.
-嗨 -现在付给她两小时的钱
-Hi. -Pay her now for two hours
然后再看情况 我会在2小时候打给你
and see how it goes. And I'll call you back in two hours.
好的 没问题
Okay. Sounds good.
要我给你倒杯红酒吗?
Can I get you a glass of wine?
当然 好啊 你想要茉莉的 柑橘的 还是香梨的?
Sure. Yeah. You want jasmine, citrus, or pear?
-什么?  -洗涤剂? 脚霜?
-What? -Lotion? Foot rub?
不 不 不 我穿着袜子就行
No, no, no. I just put my socks on.
如果你穿着袜子 我就没法给你 按摩脚底了
Well, I can't rub your feet if you're going to be wearing socks.
不 不 我以为我们要出去
No, no. I thought maybe we could go out.
-我们要出去?  -是啊 我们去吃饭
-We're going out? -Yeah, let's go to dinner.
-你是说真的吗?  -是啊 来吧
-Wh... Are you serious? -Yeah. Come on.
你是说 我们出去 然后再回来?
You mean, we're going to go out and then we come back again?
对啊 你知道 可能3小时 4小时
Yeah, you know, it could be three hours, it could be four hours.
大土豪
Big spender.
你想去哪吃? 你饿吗?
Where do you want to go? Are you hungry?
饿啊 我知道一家 你喜欢吃印度菜吗?
Yeah, I know a place. Do you like indian?
-好啊 -你不喜欢印度菜?
-Okay. -You don't like indian?
不 不 我很喜欢 很喜欢
No, no, I love it. I love it. Yeah, yeah.
-不要太辣 -不 中辣
-Not too spicy. -No, mild.
这根本不是中辣
That was not mild.
我们现在叫辆马车怎么样?
How about a carriage ride?
-我可以喘口气 -好玩!
-I could use the air. -Fun!
德里克...
Derek...
你怎么会是一个这么好的人?
How come you're such a nice guy?
-我? 是吗?  -是啊
-Me? I am? -Yeah.
是啊 真的 你真是个好人
Yeah, you are. You're a real nice guy, you know.
从来没有客户带我去喝酒
No other client ever took me for a drink,
吃饭或是坐马车 你知道吧?
or for a meal or a buggy ride, you know?
他们只想"脱 干 谢谢你 女士"
They just want to, you know, "wham, bam", thank you, ma'am.
我猜我是那种浪漫型的
I guess, I'm the romantic type.
是啊 的确
Yeah, you are.
的确 你是个浪漫的人
You are. You are a romantic guy.
你想做什么? 我是说 除了这个
What do you want to do? I mean, besides this.
你想做什么?
What do you want to do?
我想...
I want...
我想演戏
I want to act, you know.
是的 我想当演员
Yeah, I want to be an actress.
当然 那样我爸爸就会因为我演戏
But then, of course, my dad thinks I'm on cloud nine
-开心的上云霄了 -为什么?
-with the whole acting thing. -Why?
因为在我等到我的机会之前
'Cause it's like I just do this as a way to earn a living
我只是为了谋生才这么做
while I wait until my break, you know.
也能帮家里分担一些
Also help my folks out a little.
也许还有其他更好的谋生之路啊
Well, maybe there's a better way to earn a living.
你知道 当你和男人约会
Well, you know, you date guys...
他们想要什么?
What do they want?
他们想和你上床
They want you in the sack.
我见过的男人都是这样的
So this way, guys I meet, that's all they want, too,
但至少他们得为此而付钱
but at least they're gonna pay for it.
你知道 你遇到一个 没有任何非分之想的男人
You know, you meet a guy and they expect it for nothing.
这样的话 我就占优势
So this way I figure I'm ahead of the game.
但那真的让我感觉不太好 真的
But it doesn't really make me feel good, really.
我觉得你棒极了
I think you're terrific.
你知道 你算是那种 最注重细节的爱侣了!
You know, you are the most detailed kind of lover!
-注重细节?  -是啊
-Detailed? -Yeah.
感觉...非常棒
Like... That was amazing.
我真的很喜欢你
I really like you.
听着...
Listen...
你想不想很我做笔交易?
You wanna make a deal with me?
什么交易?
What kinda deal?
不 不 不 我明天就要走了
No, no, no. I'm, I'm leaving tomorrow.
但如果你...如果你今晚 庄重地对我承诺
But if you... If you promise me tonight, solemnly,
以你的人格担保
on your word of honor,
你永远不会再这么做了
that you'll never do this again,
我就给你3万美金
I'll give you $30,000.
什么...给这么多钱做爱吗?
What... To have sex?
不 不 你知道 因为钱
No, no, you know, for money.
答应我你只会在你喜欢上一个人 的时候才会这么做 而不是因为爱
Promise me you'll only do it when you, when you like someone, or for love.
就因为这个 你要给我3万?
What you're gonna give me $30,000 for that?
是啊
Yeah.
我是说 这能给你的演艺事业 一个新的开始
I mean, it'll give you a fresh start on your acting,
或是任何你想做的事
and whatever you want to do.
你真是个浪漫的人!
You are a romantic guy!
但你不是认真的吧?
But you're not really serious?
不 我是认真的 钱就在行李箱里
No, I'm serious. It's, it's in the suitcase.
没有任何附加条件 我保证 我只是...
No strings attached, I promise. I just...
我觉得你很棒
I think you're great.
真的
I do.
你知道吗 你算是第一个这么说的人
You're kinda the first one, you know?
我爸爸总说 我想去演戏真是疯了
Like, my, my dad always said that I was just crazy for wanting to act
他还说 那永远不可能 成为我的"人生位置"
and he said it was never going to be "my place in life",
他是这么说的
He called it.
-我妈妈也是 -这太荒唐了
-And my mom, too. -That's ridiculous.
没人能告诉你 你的位置在哪
Nobody can tell you where your place is.
我的位置在哪? 别人的位置在哪
Where's my place? Where's anybody's place.
你想知道在哪吗?  就在你觉得幸福的地方
You want to know where it is? Wherever you're happy.
那就是你的位置 而你就是最好的裁判
That's where your place is. And you're the best judge of that.
比如 在中央公园里
In central park, for instance,
有些人喜欢给松鼠喂坚果
some people like to feed nuts to the squirrels.
但如果喂松鼠吃坚果让某人觉得开心
But if it makes someone happy to feed squirrels to the nuts,
我凭什么说他是喂松鼠的傻瓜呢?
who am I to say nuts to the squirrels?
-你说的太好了!  -很棒吧 对
-That is just terrific! -It's good, right.
你能再亲我一次吗?
Say, could you, could you kiss me again?
在给我3万块之前?
Before the 30 grand?
你知道 这个人 这个拥有美丽心灵的人
You know, this man, this beautiful person,
他想做的 只是照顾我
all he wanted to do was care for me.
对我来说
For me...
他做到了
And he did.
而且 他在纽约改变了我的人生
And he changed my life, in a New York minute.
你知道 我对他有种
You know, I think I felt something for him
我从未对谁有过的感觉
that I never felt for anybody before.
爱吗?
Love?
感激
Gratitude.
他用我鼓舞我客户的方式鼓舞了我
He inspired me the way that I inspired my clients.
就算是缪斯女神 也需要一个女神
Even a muse needs a muse.
我会想你的 戈尔...
I'll miss you, Glo...
我是说 伊莎
I mean, Izzy.
不 我会想念你的
No, I'll miss you...
祝你旅途顺利
You have a good trip.
好的 注意安全
Okay. Be safe.
你知道 我永远不会忘记你 德里克
You know, I'll never forget you, Derek.
我也是
Me too.
贾斯汀?
Justin!
我之前和你提过的那个客户 是个法官
That client I told you about earlier, was a judge.
而且他写不出他的裁决 或是观点什么的
And he couldn't write his judgments or opinions or whatever.
所以 我帮了他一把 完全把他解救了
So, I worked with him a little bit and yeah, totally helped him out.
问题是 当你鼓舞了某个人
The problem is that when you inspire people
他们就想继续 一次一次被鼓舞
they want to keep getting inspired, over and over again.
有时候甚至是几小时
Sometimes for hours.
就像毒品 有瘾
It's like a drug. Highly addictive.
如果你得不到 你就会开始坐立不安
If you don't get it, you start to go batty.
你好 这里是薇琪公司 我们现在暂时无法接听
Hello, this is Vickie's. We're not here right now,
请留言 我们稍后将回复您
but leave a message and we'll call you back soon.
你好 薇琪吗? 我是杜力德博士
Hello, Vickie? This is Dr. Dolittle.
-你不能打给我... -喂 喂 博士
-You can't call me... -Hello, hello, Doc.
你为什么那么小声? 你在哪?  尼瓜拉加瀑布吗?
Why are you whispering? Where are you? Niagara falls?
不 不 不 我不得不给你打电话 是因为...
No, no, no. But I just had to call you because...
戈尔...你知道 我需要再见她一面
Glo... You know. I need to see her again.
-她不干了 -不干了?
-She's quit. -Quit?
-不干了是什么意思?  -不干了就是不干了
-What do you mean, quit? -Quit means quit.
你愿意找别的人吗?
Now, would you like anybody else?
我可以送一个非常漂亮的金发姑娘去
I have a very nice blond I can send over.
现在不行 我待会回给你
Not now. I'll call back.
我是薇薇安·克莱蒙特博士
This is Dr. Vivian Claremont.
我在休7年一次的年假 将在托斯卡纳区待6个月
I have gone on sabbatical and will be in Tuscany for six months.
如果有急事找我 可以告诉我女儿
Any of you who need immediate help may speak to my daughter,
找到她就等于找到了我 她的名字叫珍妮·克莱蒙特
who is very empathetic, her name is Jane Claremont.
有任何急事 请拨打她的电话
In an emergency, call her cellphone.
纽约有8百万人
Eight million people in New York
好像大家都彼此认识
and it seems like everyone knows everyone.
谁电话 能赶紧接一下吗?
Will somebody answer their God damn phone?
你母亲没给你留紧急联络方式吗?
Didn't your mother leave you an emergency line?
该死 该死!
Shit! Shit!
我可以把这想成是一种提醒我们
I like to think that coincidence is a way of reminding us
某个有伟大蓝图的人的方式的一种巧合
that there's somebody up there with a master plan.
喂? 哪位?
Yes? Hello? Who is it?
喂 是克莱蒙特的女儿吗?
Hello, is this the Claremont daughter?
对 哪位?
Yes. Who is it?
那个 我现在有紧急事故
Well, I'm having a bit of an emergency.
紧急事故? 好吧 可能只是 你觉得是紧急事故吧
An emergency? All right, you probably just think it's an emergency!
我刚把东西都掉在纽约市街头了
I have just dropped all of my stuff on the street in New York City.
这才叫紧急事故! 您的是什么?
Now, that is an emergency! What's yours?
那个 我遇到点问题 算是某种强迫症...
Well, I'm, I'm having a problem. It's kind of an obsession...
上瘾?
An obsession?
好吧 我能告诉你我的经验之谈吗
All right, can I just tell you something from experience,
强迫症并非紧急事故
obsessions are not emergencies.
这是伴随了你一辈子的事
They stick with you your entire life
所以你最好面对它 这东西会伴随你
so you better just face it, that this thing is going to be with you
非常长的时间
for a really long time.
要么你试着克服它
Either you just have to get over it,
要么就应对它 好吗?
or deal with it, all right?
所以 如果你在工作时间打给我 那很好
So, if you would like to call me during office hours, that's fine.
我周一 周二工作
I work monday, tuesday,
周三上午不工作 也就是现在
not wednesday morning, which is right now.
周四早上也不工作 也就是明天
Not thursday mornings, which is tomorrow.
所以你可以今天下午打给我
So you can call me this afternoon,
或者明天下午和周五全天 好吗?
tomorrow afternoon or friday all day, all right?
我不想被无聊的事打扰
I don't want to be bothered with nonsense.
拜托 你已经是个成年人了 成熟点!
Please, you're a grown man. Grow up!
我 我 我...
Me, me, me...
我 我 我
Me, me, me, me, me.
约书亚! 拜托 拜托 你能把狗拉住吗?
Joshua! Please, please, can you just hold the dog?
拜托 我在接电话 正在处理紧急事故
Please. I'm on the phone, I'm dealing with emergencies.
人们需要我 我是个看护员 这就是我的工作
People need me. I'm a caregiver, it's what I do and...
你知道 你真的应该对人更礼貌一些
Well, then, you know, you should really try to be more polite to people.
你今天什么毛病?
What is it with you today?
有人往你的玉米片里撒尿了吗?
Did someone take a piss in your cornflakes?
没什么 只是对明天的试镜有点紧张
Nothing. I'm just a little nervous about tomorrow's casting.
有什么大不了的? 不应该...
What is the big deal? It shouldn't...
-我说过 别打给我... -不 是我的电话
-I told you to please not call... -No, it's my phone.
爸爸 现在不是时候
It's not a good time right now, dad.
真不敢相信你是在和你爸爸说话
I cannot believe you're talking to your father.
-他刚打电话来了 -你爸爸!
-He just called. -Your father!
-我这就给他回 -拜托
-I'm calling him back. -Please!
他打电话给你...感觉你好像 每天都在过父亲节!
He calls you all the... It's like its father's day with you every day!
我是说 那个人总是打电话给你!
I mean, the guy calls you all the time!
-不 他没有 -这太奇怪了
-No, he doesn't. -It's a little weird.
-老实说 我受够了 -他只打了我一次电话
-Honestly, I'm getting fed up with it. -He's called me once.
事实上 我受够了 我走了
In fact, I am fed up with it. I'm out of here.
出租车!
Taxi!
你不要你的狗和购物袋了吗?
Don't you want your dog or your bags?
你是我见过的最无礼的人
You are the rudest person I have ever met.
走吧 谢普
Come on. Come on, shep.
出租车!
Taxi!
也许那个法官和珍妮医生 并没有我想象中那么古怪
Maybe that judge or Dr. Jane wasn't as nutty as I remember.
真乖
Good girl.
但记忆不是录像机
But memory isn't a video camera.
对吗?
Is it?
喂? 弗利特侦探 我们从来都不太忙
Hello? Fleet detectives. We're never too busy.
我不能放弃 我已经想了一晚上了
I can't give up. I've thought about it all night.
我必须见到她 这要求过分吗?
I've got to see her, is that too much to ask?
稍等 法官 她的窃听器有声音了
Just a minute, judge. Her wiretap just came on.
-发生什么事了?  -她的经纪人在呼叫她
-What's happening? -Her agent is calling her.
喂? 我给你争取了一次试镜
Hello? I've got an audition for you.
-什么时候? 几点?  -明天
-When? What time? -Tomorrow.
-11点你可以吗?  -可以 当然 我可以
-Can you make it at 11:00? -Yeah, sure. I can make that.
-是 是演什么的?  -是个主角
-What's the, what's the part? -It's a leading role.
主角? 没开玩笑吧
It's a lead? No kidding.
好 我太开心了! 什么角色?
Yeah, I'm thrilled. What's the character?
她是个妓女
She's a hooker?
-妓女?  -对
-A hooker? -Yeah.
没开玩笑吧 真有意思
No kidding. That's kind of funny.
那 那导演呢?
What... What's like the director?
阿诺德·艾伯森
Arnold Albertson.
阿诺德·艾伯森?
Arnold Albertson?
-是啊 他很厉害的 -我从没听说过他啊
-Yeah. He's very good. -Never heard of him.
-他可是顶尖导演之一 -好吧
-He's one of the best. -Okay.
-拜 -好 拜
-Bye. -All right, bye.
好吧 法官 别担心 我会跟着她
Okay, judge, don't worry. I'll follow her.
你还在跟进这个案子 我现在感觉好多了
I feel better now that you're still on the case.
-嗨 德里克 -嗨
-Hi, Derek. -Hi.
记得我吗? 伊丽莎白!
Remember me? Elizabeth!
伊丽莎白 对 我们...
Elizabeth, right. We...
喂松鼠吃坚果?
Squirrels To The Nuts?
天呐 是啊!
My God, yes!
对 芝加哥
Yes, Chicago.
不 达拉斯
No, Dallas.
达拉斯 没错 对 对
Dallas, that's right. Yes. Yes.
你最近还好吗?
How have you been?
我最近还好吗?
How have I been?
-你完全改变了我的整个人生!  -是吗?
-You absolutely changed my entire life! -Have I?
我真不敢相信我现在又撞见你了
I can't believe I'm running into you right now.
我用那笔钱开了个服装行 我刚从巴黎回来
I started a dress line with that money. I just got back from Paris.
我现在正要去里约开新店!  我最近还好吗?
I'm going to Rio to start a deal! How have I been?
好吧 很高兴见到你 我...
Well, it's great to see you, I'm just...
德里克 我怎么联系你?
Derek, how do I find you?
我觉得我在过去的40年里 都被问到这同一个问题
I feel like I've been asking myself the same question the last 40 years.
而我依然不知道 但 听着
And I still don't know, but listen,
我现在有点急事 但我们 还有达拉斯的回忆
I'm just rushing off, but we'll always have Dallas
所以 我很高兴能够帮到你
and I'm so happy I was able to help.
好吧 再次感谢你
Okay, well, thank you again.
-希望能再见到你 -我知道
-And I hope I see you again. -I know.
好 好...
Okay. Okay...
所以 也还有其他人 他帮助过我 也帮助过她们
So there were others. He helped me and he helped them.
我不是说 他这么做是对的
And I'm not saying what he did was right.
我并没有护着他
I'm not defending him.
但他纯粹是为了高兴而这么做
But he did it for the high,
而每次高兴过后 就是毁灭
and after every high there always comes the crash.
阿诺德!
Arnold!
坐飞机还顺利吗?
How was the flight?
我的一个客户给了我一次 一生的治疗 作为礼物
One of my clients gave me a lifetime of therapy as a gift.
我的治疗师是个酒鬼
And my therapist was a drunk.
所以她就离开去戒酒了 她的女儿 珍妮医生接手了她的工作
So she left to dry out. Her daughter took over, Dr. Jane.
而且她写了这本书
And she wrote this book
《找到你的柔软面》 你知道这本书吗?
finding your softer side. Do you know it?
-不知道 -大畅销书
-No. -Big best-seller.
她看起来是个很可爱的女人 而且我和她聊天很兴奋
She seemed like a sweet woman and I was excited to talk to her.
是啊 是啊 我妈妈已经去了3个月了
Yes, yes. My mother has been gone for three months.
如果你想和我聊 可以
If you would like to talk to me, fine.
如果你不想和我聊 也可以
If you would not like to talk to me, that's fine.
-你决定了吗?  -不
-Have you decided? -No.
不 我是说 我想和你聊聊
No. I mean, I'd like to talk to you.
她去年和一个性感的瑜伽老师
She'd been through a rough break up the year before
分手了
with a hot yoga teacher.
我是说 瑜伽很性感 不是指那个老师
Well, I mean, the yoga was hot, not the teacher.
事实上 那个老师也很性感 但这不是重点
Well, actually, the teacher was, too, but that's not the point.
他们在课上认识的 他开始给她上私人课程
They meet in class, and he starts to give her these private lessons.
然后就开始一起住了 结果是
And then they move in together. It turns out
他也给其他的女人上私人课程
he had been giving every other woman in the class private lessons, too.
你能想象吗?
Can you imagine?
我是说 她的新书叫 《犯贱之美》也就不奇怪了
I mean, no wonder her latest book is called Bitchy Is Beautiful.
那本书我看过 对
That one I read. Yeah.
-好吧 请坐 -好 谢谢
-All right, have a seat. -Yeah, thanks.
我看了你的文件 你叫什么来着?
So, I've taken a look at your file. What's your name again?
伊莎
Izzy.
那是昵称吗? 全名叫什么?
That's short for something. What's your full name?
抱歉你说什么?
I beg your pardon?
你全名叫什么? 集中注意
What's your full name? Pay attention!
我叫伊莎贝拉
My name is Isabella.
好 伊莎贝拉
There. Isabella.
而你把它缩减为伊莎
And you've cut it down to Izzy.
那意味着你把你身上的可爱之处缩减了
That means you are cutting off the sweet part of yourself
因为伊莎贝拉很甜美 而伊莎很坚硬
because Isabella is so sweet and Izzy is so hard.
这就能看出你的一些性格
There's some insight into your personality right there.
似乎你对你甜美的一面感到不牢靠
It seems that you're insecure with your sweet self,
所以你强调那个坚强的自己
so you're emphasizing your tough self.
我说的对不对? 你文件在哪呢?
Am I right or am I wrong? Where's your file?
好吧...
Okay...
亦称为戈尔...为什么还有别名?
A.K.A. Glo stick... Why A.K.A. Anyway? Do...
应召女郎?
Call girl?
好恶心
Well, that's disgusting.
我是说 你在做那种事的时候什么感觉
I mean, how do you feel when you're even doing that?
说真的
Honestly.
这份工作有任何积极点吗?
Are there any up sides to this job?
积极点非常多啊 这真的不算问题
Well, there were a lot of ups... That wasn't really the problem.
你不能在做心理治疗的时候开玩笑
You don't joke in therapy.
我只是 有点紧张
I'm just... I'm feeling kind of nervous.
你知道 明天我有个真的很重要的面试
You know, I've got this really important audition tomorrow.
什么? 你要面试当应召女郎?
What? So you're auditioning to be a call girl?
不 不 不 我那样做
No, no, no. I do that on the side,
只是为了帮助我演戏
like, just to kind of support my acting.
所以你是要去试镜
So you have an audition.
-什么角色?  -应召女郎
-What's the role? -A call girl.
等等 我刚问过你了
Wait, I just asked you that.
我知道 真的很讽刺
I know, it's so ironic,
但人生有时候就是这样
but life is like that sometimes.
好吧 那太好了 至少你经验丰富
All right, well that's great. At least you have a lot of experience.
该死!
Shit!
-稍等 -喂? 嗨!
-Hold on a second. -Hello? Hi!
你听得到吗?
Can you hear me?
我猜你可能正在做治疗
I guess you're probably in a session.
好极了 是我妈 她喝醉了!
Great, it's my mother. She's drunk!
他会咬人吗?
Does he bite?
我不知道 要看情况
I don't know. It depends.
好吧 因为...
Yeah, 'cause...
你在干什么? 抱歉!
What are you doing? Excuse me!
请从椅子上下来
Please get off the chair.
-你疯了吗?  -我真的不太喜欢狗
-Are you insane? -I don't really like dogs.
不喜欢狗
Don't like dogs.
过来 过来
Come on. Come on.
快点 走 走!
Go on, scram! Scram.
快点
Come on.
老天 毫无疑问 你真是神经过敏
God, you're neurotic, that's for sure.
我妈妈正从比萨的一家 戒瘾所给我打电话
My mother's calling from a Detox Center outside of Pisa.
喂 我真的需要找个人
Hello, I really need to speak to somebody
说说我的强迫症问题 也许我可以预约
about my obsessional problem. Maybe I could make an appointment.
我现在濒临崩溃边缘 非常崩溃
I'm on the Verge here... The very Verge.
这声音听起来好熟悉啊
That voice sounds so familiar...
是啊 它现在也开始让我 听起来觉得熟悉了
Yeah, well, it's starting to sound way too familiar to me.
这家伙完全是个笨蛋
That guy is a total loon!
但我不能说我客户的坏话
But I cannot talk about my clients.
我不能说我的客户
I cannot talk about my clients...
因为这很隐私
Because that's private.
所以我不能告诉你那是谁 所以别问我
So I can't tell you who it is, so don't ask me.
现在 我说到哪了?
Now, where was I?
如果你愿意接受自己柔软的一面
So if you would just embrace the softer side of yourself,
不再生活在坚硬的边缘
and stop living on that hard edge,
你的状态会好一些
you would be in such better shape.
开始叫自己伊莎贝拉
Just start calling yourself Isabella
也许你能解决很多 也许不是全部的问题
and you may solve many, if not all, of your problems.
今天我已经放弃当应召女郎了
Well, today I've stopped being a call girl.
太好了!
That's great!
太棒了! 你看到治疗的好处了吧?
That's great! You see how therapy works!
就像...就像一块瑞士表
It's like a... It's like a swiss clock.
太棒了 你不再需要治疗了 我们的疗程结束了
That's fabulous. You don't need therapy any more. We're finished.
给自己找条大狗 他们是很好的伴侣
Just get yourself a large dog... They're great company.
祝贺你 伊莎...伊莎贝拉
Congratulations, Izzy... Isabella.
你毕业了
You've graduated.
那个 你的名字是人们首先 了解到你的事
Well, your name is the first thing people learn about you.
你知道 这是他们看待你 觉得你是什么样的人的依据
You know, it's how they think of you. It's who you are.
珍妮告诉我的 但...
Dr. Jane gave me that, but...
我不再是来自布鲁克林的伊莎怪人了
I wasn't going to be Izzy Finklestein from Brooklyn any more.
我将做伊莎贝拉·帕特森
I was going to be Isabella Patterson.
从我想开始的地方开始
From wherever I wanted to be.
见到你太高兴了!
What a thrill to see you walk in!
-德尔塔 你认识乔什?  -当然
-Delta, you know Josh? -Of course.
约书亚 你的剧越来越好了
Your play's only gotten better, Joshua.
谢谢! 等不及看到你表演了
Thank you! I can't wait to see you do it.
嘿 伙计们 抱歉 我迟到了
Hey, guys, sorry I'm late.
当然 你们都认识赛斯
And you know Seth, of course.
我们认识吗? 自从伦敦以后 多久没见了?
Do we know each other? How long's it been since London?
太久了 亲爱的
Too long, dear.
过来
Come here.
很高兴见到你
Nice to meet you.
我们去把大家都召齐吧 珊迪!
Let's get everybody going. Sandy!
-你看起来美极了 -赛斯 你真会说话
-You're looking gorgeous. -Seth, you're such a charmer.
好吧 但愿如此
Well, I hope so.
你知道赛斯·吉尔伯特会去试镜吗?
Did you know Seth Gilbert was going to be at the audition?
不 不知道
No. No idea.
我甚至不知道继那些电影之后 他还演戏
I didn't even know he did theater any more, since those movies.
记得他有个穿着粉色蝴蝶袖
What's the one where he had like pink, fluffy sleeves
腰带上还挂着小蜜蜂的造型吗?
and the trained Bumble Bee in his belt buckle?
-《红峰侠》?  -对...
-Red Bee man? -Yeah...
看完5部之后 我就不再关注他了
Well, after all five of those I sort of stopped following him.
那德尔塔·西蒙斯呢?
What about Delta Simmons?
你想听一些真正有趣的事吗?
You want, you want to hear something really funny?
当然
Sure.
又一次 她去了沙龙 我妈妈给她洗头
One time, she comes into the salon and my ma washes her hair.
于是就有了妈妈和德尔塔 在假火炉上的照片
So we got this picture of ma and Delta above the fake fireplace.
说说宇宙力量吧
Talk about cosmic forces...
现在我有机会跟她合作
Now, I had the chance to work with her.
这就是命运 但我一直没有机会告诉她
It was fate, but I never got to tell her.
让我问你一个问题
"Let me just ask you one question.
你答不答应 任何时候当我问...
"Do you promise that whenever I ask the...
任何时候当我告诉你什么
"Whenever I tell you something
你永远会站在我身旁 而且你永远不会...
"that you'll always stand by me and that you'll never be...
你永远会是我的朋友 而且你永远...
"That you'll always be my friend, and that you'll always...
你是否答应不管我告诉你什么...
Do you promise that no matter what I tell you..."
制片人的女儿
Producer's daughters...
你是否答应无论如何 你永远会是我的朋友
"Do you promise that no matter what, you'll always be my friend..."
太好了 谢谢 很完美
Great, thank you. That was excellent.
我觉得你有点年轻 不过太感谢你来了
I think you're a little bit young, but thanks so much for coming in.
-谢谢 -谢谢
-Thank you! -Thank you!
很好 亲们
Very good, darlings.
好 珊迪 下一个
Okay, Sandy, next!
这是伊莎贝拉·帕特森
This is Isabella Patterson.
天啊
Goodness!
嘿 嘿
Hey, hey, hey!
我们开始了
There we are.
-抱歉 我太紧张了 -别紧张 放松点
-Sorry. I'm so nervous. -Don't be nervous. Just relax.
天啊 不 该死
Jesus, no! God damn it!
她不对
She's not right.
-为什么?  -因为她不是合适的类型
-Why not? -Because she's not the right type.
-乔什 -我觉得她样貌很适合
-Josh... -I think she looks great for it.
放松点
Just relax.
准备好了吗 伊莎贝拉?
Are you okay, Isabella?
如果你不舒服...
If you're not feeling well...
珊迪 为什么不给她点信息
Sandy, why don't we get her information
然后下次等你更有感觉的时候再来呢
and come back another time when you're feeling more up for it.
不幸的是她病了
She's sick, unfortunately.
不不 我更想今天就完成
No, no, I'd rather do it today
因为我今天观星
because I looked at astrology zone today
星象告诉我今天对我来说 是个特别的日子
and it said it was going to be a special day for me.
好吧 我们不想就这个问题争吵
Okay, well, we don't want to argue with that.
继续吧
Let's proceed.
也许会收到惊喜呢
Maybe we'll get surprised.
我准备了3场戏
So, I've prepared three scenes.
我们只拍一场 因为现在压力很大
We're only going to do one because we're under a lot of pressure.
好吧
Okay...
那我要演哪个?
So which one should I do?
阿诺德 你觉不觉得我们应该 先拍我的亲密戏?
Arnold, don't you think we should do the intimate scene with me?
不不 我们要拍两个女人那场
No, no. We're going to do the scene with the two women.
你看着很眼熟 你最近是不是去过巴克利银行?
You look familiar. Were you at the barclay recently?
没
No.
赛斯 这场戏里没你
Seth, you're not in this scene.
你可以深呼吸一下 咱们让女士们开始吧
So, why don't you take a breather and we'll let the ladies begin.
对不起
I'm sorry.
你没事吧 亲爱的? 要歇会吗?
Are you okay, dear? Do you need a second?
-不用 -你确定?
-No. -Sure?
对 我没事
Yeah, I'm fine.
你真的不要喝一杯?
"You sure you don't want a drink?"
不不 我只是不知道从哪开始
"No, no. I just don't know where to start."
你想从哪开始都行
"Well, start anywhere you like."
我只是不知道一切是 怎么发生的 但是...
"I just don't know how it all happened, but...
这是个很希腊式的夜晚
"It was sort of a very grecian evening.
你看
"You see,
我这有一大堆工作...
"I got into this line of work where you usually...
在你见证自己最终的命运之前?
"You don't know who you're going to end up with
你不知道自己最后会遇到什么人
"until you get to your destination.
有点像是喜欢 但不亲密
Sort of like a temp, but more intimate."
你说什么呢
"What are you talking about?"
这挺难的
"Well, this is really difficult.
因为你是我非常亲密的朋友 我真的会把一切都告诉你
"Because you are my very close friend and I do tell you everything
所以我才要告诉你这个
"and that's why I'm telling you this.
不然如果我不在乎你 我也不会告诉你
"Otherwise if I didn't care for you, I wouldn't tell you.
我本来可以永远是你最好的朋友
"And I could go on forever being your best friend
你真的不会知道 但我真的需要告诉你
"and you really wouldn't have to know, but I really need to tell you."
-你说什么呢 -这...
-"What are you talking about?" -"Well...
我以前是应召女郎
"I was a call girl
而且我就是个阴招女郎
"and I pretty much am a call girl."
应召女郎!
"A call girl!"
我问你一个问题
"Let me just ask you one question.
不管我说什么
"No matter what I say,
请别用有色眼镜看我
"Please don't judge me
不管我告诉你什么 答应我 你永远会是我的朋友
"And whatever I tell you, promise me you'll always be my friend
你会永远站在我身边
"and you'll always stand by me."
当然 什么都行
"Of course. Anything.
我在乎你
"I care about you.
但我也非常非常震惊
"But I'm also very, very shocked.
我还感觉难过 那些堕落的混蛋
"And I also feel so sad. Those rotten bastards!"
这么说吧
"Put it this way.
你想不想听坏消息?
"Do you want the bad news?
或者很坏很坏的消息?
"Or the bad, bad news?
还是你想听最坏最坏的消息?
"Or do you want the bad, bad, bad news?"
天啊 还有吗
"My God, there's more?
好吧 就说坏消息吧
"Okay, give me the bad news."
避孕套破了
"The condom broke."
-不 -没错
-"No..." -"Yeah.
很坏很坏的消息是我怀孕了
"And the bad, bad news is that I'm pregnant."
-天啊 -是啊
-"God!" -"Yeah..."
看来我要当阿姨了 也没那么糟
"Well, I guess I'll be an auntie... That's not so bad."
那...
"Well...
最坏最坏的消息?
"The bad, bad, bad news?"
什么?
"Yes?"
天啊...
"Gosh..."
什么? 告诉我
"What? Tell me."
爸爸是你的弗雷德
"It was your Fred.
请别恨我 也别恨他
"Please don't hate me. And don't hate him.
这只是生活中遇到的那种
"It was just one of those crazy, stupid, weird things
疯狂 愚蠢 怪异的事情
"that happen to you in life
你无法预测 也不能批判
"and you can't predict it and you can't judge it!
所以求你 求你别恨我
"So please... Please don't hate me."
太聪明了 亲爱的 太棒了
That was brilliant, darling. That was so good!
亲爱的 她是不是演得很好 阿诺德?
Darling. Wasn't she so good, Arnold?
很好
Very good.
非常感谢你来 我们要迟了 所以..
Thank you so much for coming, we're running late, so...
我送她出去 珊迪 你把 下一个女孩带进来
I'll show her out, Sandy. You bring in the next girl.
-很好 伊莎贝拉 -多谢
-Very good, Isabelle. -Thanks a lot.
-好 再见 -再见
-Yeah. Bye. -Goodbye!
嘿 我送你出去
Hey, I'll walk you out.
干得好
Well done.
她是不是很棒?
Wasn't she good?
是的 非常棒 无可匹敌
She was. Very. She nailed it!
她是不是很棒 阿诺德?
Wasn't she good, Arnold?
她确实不错
I did think she was good.
她真的感动我了
She really moved me.
好吧 下一个是谁? 咱们继续
Okay, so what's next? Let's move on...
-那么 你是应召女郎?  -在戏里是
-So, you were a call girl? -In the play.
不 你暗示的可不是那样
No, that's not what you've been implying.
对 不是 伊莎是应召女
Yeah, no. Izzy was. Yeah.
但你是伊莎
But you're Izzy.
我是
I am.
那你今晚有没有空来吃个晚饭?
So, are you by any chance free for dinner tonight?
我不知道 估计有吧
I don't know. Yeah, I guess.
好 好
Good. Good.
你今天的表演太震撼了
I was so impressed with that reading today.
不过说实话 在试镜之前 我就已经对你印象深刻了 所以...
But, to be honest, I was impressed before the reading too, so...
多谢
Well, thanks a lot.
嗯
Yeah.
你是不是很了解阿诺德·艾伯森?
Do you know Arnold Albertson that well?
对 我了解他 但不是特别了解
Yeah, I know him. But not very well.
他帮我做这部戏一年了 怎么了?
He's helped me with the play for a year. Why?
没什么 只是他看起来像个好人
Nothing. He just seemed like a really nice guy.
对 尼西亚意大利的吗?
Yeah... Do you like italian?
意大利菜
Food.
好啊 当然
Yeah, sure.
第五大道的尼克饭店怎么样?
How about Nicks on Fifth?
还是我去你家接你?
Or should I pick you up at home?
不不 我在饭店见你吧
No, no, no. I'll meet you at the restaurant.
-几点?  -8点?
-What time? -Eight o'clock?
好 没问题 到时候见
Okay, sure. I'll see you then.
好 不过别告诉其他人我约了你
Okay. Don't tell anybody, but I'm rooting for you.
非常感谢
Thanks a lot.
-回头见 -好
-I'll see you later. -Okay.
再见
Bye.
你知不知道电影《蒂凡尼的早餐》?
Do you know the movie breakfast at Tiffany's?
-知道 -这...
-Yes. -Well...
他们在城里什么地方放 我看到张海报
They were playing it somewhere downtown and I see this poster
上面的奥德丽美极了
of Audrey looking so gorgeous.
所以我就买了张票进场
So I bought a ticket and I went in.
连续几星期这部电影 都在我脑海里挥之不去
And, for weeks I couldn't get this movie out of my head, you know?
她把一切都掌握在手心里
She had everything under control.
所有问题都搞定了 她什么都不需要
Everything figured out, she didn't need anything...
她是个应召女郎
She is a call girl.
也许她只是一个喜欢喝酒跳舞
Well, maybe she was just somebody who liked to have a drink and a dance
传播快乐的女孩
and spread happiness,
如果有个人愿意在她去 化妆间的路上塞给她50块
and if a guy was going to give her 50 on the way to the powder room
那也是她应得的 因为她 触碰了他们的生活
then she deserved it because she touched their lives.
我很清楚这是一种痴迷
I'm perfectly aware that it's an obsession.
但也许我对那个女人本人更了解
But maybe if I knew more about the woman herself...
对 那这个让她
Yes, what is it about this woman
如此沉迷的女人到底有什么特别的
that makes her so goddamn obsessionable?
她说话不像我奶奶
She doesn't sound like my grandmother.
什么?
Say, what?
我认识的每个女人说话都像我奶奶
Every woman I've ever known sounds like my grandmother,
除了这个
except for this one.
戈尔
Glo...
戈尔?
Glo?
"荧光棒"那种?
As in Glo stick?
是的 怎么了
Why, yes. Why?
我的天
My God.
"我的天"什么意思
What do you mean, "My God?"
我是说 天啊 太棒了
I mean... My God! That's terrific!
真是个好名字
What a terrific... Terrific name.
对 那名字可不是人人都能想到的
Yeah, you don't come across that name too often.
不 但你的治疗 看上去是很普通的疗程
No, but in therapy you do. It's kinda common in therapy.
你知道"荧光棒"?
You know a Glo stick?
对 我知道好吗?  实际上我就是她的治疗师
Yes, I do. Okay? In fact, I am her therapist.
但专业原因让我无法讨论
But professional reasons make it impossible for me to discuss
有关她的任何话题
anything whatsoever to do with her.
但她是个很好的女人
She's a very nice woman, however.
她有点神经质 而且有一些别的小问题
She's a little neurotic and she has got quite a few problems
并且需要接触她内心柔软的部分
and she needs to get in touch with her softer side.
但那...那是隐私 那是隐私 我是医生
But that's... That's private! That is private! I am a doctor.
医生不能讨论病人的私生活
Doctors do not discuss their patients' private lives.
要是我的下一个客人跑进来
How would you like it if I my next client walked in here
听到我说刚走出去的那个人
and I said that the guy that just walked out of here
是个痴迷于名叫"荧光棒"的 女人的变态怪胎会怎么想?
Is a lunatic weirdo obsessed with a woman named Glo stick?
你会怎么想?
How would you like that?
这...
Well...
顺便 我觉得不管这女孩多有魅力
And by the way, I don't think that this girl, however attractive,
都不值得你这样跪舔
is worth being obsessed about.
特别是不能用其他人的婚姻观来评判她
Especially for a married judge of other humans.
我不是有偏见 但这就是太愚蠢了
Now, I'm not judgmental, but that's just stupid!
是我 乔什 能借吗
It's me, Josh. Can you pick up?
看我这治疗师干得多棒
See what a good therapist I am?
那是我男朋友 而且我不打算接
That's my boyfriend and I'm not picking up.
这是你的专属时间
This is your private time.
我今晚要加班搞这部戏的工作 没法去吃晚饭了 真对不起
So, I'm kind of stuck with the play tonight and I can't make it for dinner.
什么意思? 你不能来吃晚饭是什么意思
What do you mean? What do you mean you can't make it to dinner?
行 你知道吗? 我饿死算了
Fine! You know what? I'll starve.
我以前就挨过饿 再挨饿算什么
I've starved before, I'll starve again.
最近我经常饿肚子
You know, I've been starving a lot myself lately.
也许我们可以一起挨饿呢
Perhaps we should starve together.
今晚愿意跟我一起吃晚饭吗?
Would you care to have dinner with me tonight?
你平时都吃什么菜?
What kind of food do you eat?
意大利菜你喜欢吗?
Do you like italian?
还行
It's all right.
-那么?  -好吧
-So? -All right.
我去换个卫生棉
I'm going to change my tampon.
对不起 我只是不同意你的
I'm sorry, I just... I don't agree with you.
我觉得那个叫帕特森的女孩 就像赛斯说的 "无人能敌"
I just think that Patterson girl "nailed it," as Seth put it.
她身上有种别人都没有的感觉
I just think that there was something about her that nobody else had.
有种经验丰富的感觉 就好像她有过那种生活
Kind of an experienced quality. Almost like she'd lived it.
对 我得说 我同意德尔塔 和赛斯的说法
Yeah, I have to say, I agree with Delta and Seth.
她确实有些地方非常非常特别
I mean, she had something really, really special.
她让我想起了我在幼儿园 爱上的那个女孩
She reminds me of the girl that I fell in love with in kindergarten.
她是站街女吗
Was she a hooker?
对 她是幼儿园的站街女
Yeah, she was a kindergarten hooker.
这学校有点前卫啊
That sounds like a progressive school.
好了 珊迪 还有谁我们没讨论到
Okay, Sandy, who have we not discussed?
都说到了
You've covered it.
好的 那么不如今晚就到这 大家回去睡觉
Okay, well, why don't we call it a night and sleep on it.
不过那个伊莎
That Izzy, though,
我好像在哪见过她
I feel like I know her from somewhere.
她确实有张大众脸
Well, she did have one of those sort of ordinary faces
很多人都跟她长得像
that are a dime a dozen, so...
我不这么觉得
I don't think so.
那我咋知道 我现在饿得 都没法思考了
Well, what do I know? I'm so hungry I can't even think straight right now.
好 那就到此为止
Okay, looks like that's a wrap.
好
Okay.
你今天真是前所未有得美
You're looking more beautiful than ever.
我都等不及了 特别是床戏
I can't wait to do this... Especially the love scenes.
快走了
Get out of here.
谢谢你 导演先生
Well, thank you, Mr. Director,
真是个充满惊喜的第一天 对吧
that was a very surprising first day, wasn't it?
是的 所以我们才专门 跑到剧院来被惊喜
It sure was, yeah. That's why we go to the theater... To be surprised.
不过 你也许需要在明天
Incidentally, you might find a few more colors
你的表演力多拿出点色彩来
in your performance tomorrow in rehearsals.
不过今天干得不错 我们只是刚开始
But good job today. We're just beginning.
如果我太严厉了 对不起
Hey, sorry if I was a little snappy, darling.
不如咱们去吃个浪漫晚餐怎么样
But, why don't I make it up with a little romantic dinner?
请问需要什么 先生
Can I help you, sir?
一人的桌 要那边的
Table for one, over there.
这边请
This way, please.
嗨
Hi!
Hi.
真对不起我迟到了
I'm so sorry I'm late.
天啊 你没事吧
My God, are you all right?
没事 没事
It's all right, it's all right.
不不 我扶你起来
No, no... Let me get you up.
您要先来杯水吗
May I offer you some water?
-不 -威士忌加苏打?
-No. -Scotch and soda?
-也许吧 -我去叫
-Maybe. -I'll look into it.
-谢谢 -很荣幸
-Thank you. -My pleasure.
真漂亮的饭店
Such a beautiful restaurant.
嗯哼
Ahem!
-你怎么了?  -没事 没事
-What's your problem? -Nothing, nothing...
只是渴了
I'm just... I was thirsty.
谢谢
Thank you.
你怎么回事?
What is it with you?
我不知道我怎么了 只是太渴了
I don't know what's the matter with me. I'm just very thirsty.
那把杯子拿起来啊 别把杯子推下去
Well, then pick up the glass! Stop pushing it off the table.
你小时候肯定很任性
You must have been such a demanding child.
天啊 我饿死了
God, I'm just starving.
反正 就像我说的 我真受不了那些艺术家
Anyway, as I was saying, I'm just so sick of artists.
他们总是让你失望
They just always let you down.
给我个优秀的商人就行了
Just give me a great businessman.
跟这个剧作家约会 他们写喜剧
Dating this playwright... They write plays,
却根本不考虑生活 他们...
they don't think about life, they...
你有在听我的话吗
Are you listening to anything that I'm saying?
还有为什么藏在菜单后面
And why are you hiding behind that menu?
我没有
I'm not!
律师 好人 对 对
Lawyers, good people. Yes. Yes.
我只是得改变一下我的生活 我就是这个意思 我必须改变
I just have to change my life, that's all I can say. I have to.
你在看什么?
What are you looking at?
我没看错吧?
Is that who I think it is?
那王八蛋
That son of a bitch!
天啊 你没事吧?
My gosh! Are you all right?
-没事 没事 -怎么今天一个个都倒了
-Yeah, yeah. -Everybody keeps falling down!
喔 真棒啊 我的治疗师
Wow, how great! Here's my therapist...
珍妮 听我说 你得...
Jane, look, you have to...
你被开除了
You're fired!
乔什
Josh!
你没事吧
Are you okay?
-没事 我没事 -你确定?
-Yeah. Yeah, I'm fine. -You sure?
-没事 -你认识她?
-Yeah. -Do you know her?
是啊 我想我认识
Yeah, I guess I do.
别这么走啊
Don't just leave!
你也被开除了
You're fired, too!
看着点鹿
Watch where you're going!
你...
You...
我要去趟洗手间
I have got to go to the ladies room.
-你没事吧 儿子 -爸爸
-Are you all right, son? -Dad!
-你在这干什么?  -我在这工作
-What are you doing here? -I work here.
-什么时候开始的?  -说来话长
-From when? -It's a long story,
我们都没时间听故事
and neither of us has time for it.
一会见
I'll see you in a minute.
我去趟洗手间
I'm going to use the rest room.
珍妮 等等
Jane! Wait!
你好啊 完美试镜的美女
Well, hello, wonderful reading!
我只是呼吸点新鲜空气
I was just getting some air.
当然
Of course.
乔什 你在这干什么?
Josh, what are you doing here?
阿诺德 嗨
Arnold. Hi.
德尔塔总是说这是个好地方
Delta always said this was a great place
-所以我就想来尝尝看 -是啊 是啊
-so I thought I'd try it. -Yeah, yeah.
我跟那个叫伊莎的女孩一起来的 他太让我震惊了
I'm here with that girl, Izzy. I was so impressed with her.
-她在这?  -对 在女厕所
-She's here? -Yeah. In the ladies room.
耶稣我了个基督啊
Dear God in heaven.
什么?
What?
你怎么...
Why would you...
-法官 咱们去走走吧 -我不想走走
-Judge, let's take a little walk. -I don't want a little walk.
我要回去看看怎么回事
I'm going back in there and see what's going on!
现在不行 法官
Not right now, judge.
我听不懂你的话
Well, I can't follow anything you say.
我们现在就走
Let's not blow it now.
看看我在女厕所找到谁了
Look who I found in the ladies room.
-乔什 -啊
-Josh... -Yeah.
乔什跟我说了
Josh told me.
-你好吗 -很好 谢谢
-How are you? -I'm fine, thanks.
-你出手真快 乔什 -不 我只是...
-Fast moves, Josh. -No, I just...
你看过菜单了吗 阿诺德?
Have you had a chance to look at the menu yet, Arnold?
还好我们的孩子爱他们的祖父母
Luckily, our kids love their grandparents,
不过今晚真的应该去接他们 对吧亲爱的?
but we really should try to tuck them in tonight, right, darling?
我不太舒服 我还是先走吧
You know, I don't feel too good. I think I'm gonna go.
-不 -对不起
-No. -I'm sorry.
-好好照顾自己 -对
-Feel better. -Yeah.
照顾好自己
Feel better.
看看谁来了 稍等 迪米特里
Well, look whose here. One minute, Dmitri.
嘿 戈尔 居然是你
Hey, Glo! What do ya know?
你在跟我说话? 不 我是伊莎贝拉
You talking to me? No, I'm Isabella.
你们俩认识?
You two know each other?
不 不熟
No. Not really.
对 我搞错了
Yeah, my mistake.
大伙儿都到了 开会呢这是
The gang's all here. Of all the gin joints...
德尔塔 你比上次在皮卡迪利大街
Delta, you look even younger now than you did that time in Piccadilly
跟那些孩子们玩的适合还更年轻 你记得吗?
when you played with those children. Remember?
那次很开心 不是吗
That was fun, wasn't it?
很高兴见到你吗 但我真的该走了
It was really nice to see you all, but I gotta go.
-照顾好自己 -对
-Feel better. -Yes.
-明天见 -咱们去坐下 弗兰基
-See you tomorrow. -Let's sit down, Frankie.
阿诺德
Arnold,
弗兰基是薇琪的朋友
Frankie is friends with Vickie.
我不认识什么叫薇琪的
I don't know any Vickies.
我的错
My mistake.
-肯定是认错人了 -对
-Must be some other guy. -Yeah.
今晚好像大家都犯糊涂了 肯定是天气的问题
Everybody seems to be confused tonight! Must be the weather.
是啊
Yeah.
混乱之治
Confusion reigns.
早上见
See you in the morning.
晚安 甜美的公主
Good night, sweet princess.
再见
Adieu.
晚安
Good night.
再见
Adieu.
你为什么不喜欢那女孩?
Why don't you like that girl?
-哪个女孩 -伊莎贝拉·帕特森
-Which girl? -Isabella Patterson.
谁说我不喜欢她?
Who said I don't like her?
你在她身边就很奇怪
Well, you certainly act weird around her.
奇怪? 我都没怎么看过她
Act weird? I barely even looked at her.
没错
Exactly.
这也比跟我们的型男赛斯先生 搂搂抱抱要好
It's better, it's better than swooning over Mr. Seth Seduction.
我是说 他说的话加上你的动作 简直是最搞笑的东西
I mean, everything he says you act like it's the funniest thing you ever heard.
天啊 你总是吃醋
Pish-Tosh... You're always jealous.
为什么不管说什么最后都会 扯回到伦敦和皮卡迪利大街
Why is everything always back to London and Piccadilly?
还有你们的那段风光时刻
And this glorious time you guys had.
那部戏我们配合的很好 你知道的
We had a good time on that play, you know that.
对 我知道 对不起
No, I know. I'm sorry.
他们在那
There they are!
-法官 -什么
-Judge... -What?
很抱歉 但我得告诉你问题出现了
I'm sorry to tell you, but a problem has come up...
那是我儿子
That's my son.
那是你儿子?
That's your son?
这里有些东西不符合犹太教义 这事情发生多久了?
There's something not kosher here. How long has this been going on?
你说什么呢? 我半小时前 还什么都不知道
What are you talking about? I didn't know anything until half an hour ago,
如果你说的是这个
if that's what you're implying.
我闻到了老鼠
I smell a rat.
是吗? 我也是
Ha, you do? So do I!
-等等 等等 -我受够了被伤害
-Wait, wait, wait! -I'm tired of being abused.
希望你现在感觉好点了
I hope you're feeling better now.
我没事
Yeah, I'm okay.
但你呢 你什么都没吃
But you, you didn't get anything to eat.
要不要进来吃个三明治?
You want to come in and have a sandwich?
好啊
-Sure. -Okay.
该死的摔跤比赛
God damn wrestling match!
能别抱怨了吗
Would you stop complaining?
闭嘴 我都听不到电视了
Shut up! I can't hear the TV.
你才闭嘴 去高速公路上玩去
You shut up! Go play on the highway!
怎么了?
What's normal?
他是我认识的第一个编剧
He was the first playwright that I ever met.
而且是个真正的绅士
And he was a true gentleman, you know?
他都没想过亲我 即使我知道他很想
He didn't even try to kiss me, even when I knew he wanted to.
他还说要见见我父亲
And, he asked to meet my father.
从没人那么做过
And no one had ever done that before.
我以前从没带男孩进过家门
I never even had a boy in the house before.
不过...对 他完全就是 我想象中的编剧
But... Yeah, he was exactly what I imagined a playwright to be.
非常敏感 而且他就像我的 玛丽琳的亚瑟·米勒
Very sensitive and, he was like the Arthur Miller to my Marilyn.
三明治很好吃 谢谢
That was a great sandwich. Thanks.
你没事吧? 你好像很伤心
Are you okay? You seem a little sad.
没事 只是...
Yeah, it's just...
我觉得可能我得不到那个角色
I don't think I'm gonna get the part.
我觉得很有可能
I feel very optimistic about it.
你真好
You're very sweet.
我能给你打电话吗
May I call you?
好啊
Yeah.
当然 为什么不呢
Sure. Why not?
谢谢你让我的戏更精彩
Well, thanks for making my play better.
再见 乔什
So long, Josh.
那个叫洛雷塔的女孩试镜还不错
That Loretta girl gave a fair reading...
伊莎贝拉非常优秀
Isabella gave a brilliant one.
你今天就要作出决定
You have to make a decision today.
没有问题 没人说有问题
It's not a problem. No one said anything about a problem.
-只是我得有个过程 好吗 -过程?
-It's just that I have a process, okay? -A process?
这个过程就从百吉饼开始
And the process begins with a bagel.
-你只要按下扳机 -我吃饭不说话 亲爱的
-Pull the rigger, darling. -I'm eating in silence, honey.
-来吧 -阿诺德
-Come on. -Arnold!
去61大道和麦迪逊大街交叉口
We're going to go to 61st and Madison.
天气真不错 对吧
Lovely day, isn't it?
他很健谈 不是吗
Well, he's a talker, isn't he?
他们给的百吉饼口味错了
They gave me the wrong bagels...
我要的是罂粟籽的 他们给了我4个...
I asked for poppy seed. They gave me four...
你今天心情不错啊
Boy, are you in a mood today!
根本没人吃的东西
Which nobody eats.
告诉我你为什么不喜欢她?
Tell me why you don't like her?
谁说我不喜欢她?  我只是不想仓促选择
Who said that I don't like her? I just don't want to make a snap decision.
-仓促选择 -这太重要了 得一步步来
-A snap decision. -It's too important. It's my process.
是谁总说你得有胆量
Who is the one who always says you have to go with your gut
别瞻前顾后的?
and not think about things too much?
-可不是我说的 -那是直接饮用
-All right, not me. -That was a direct quote...
我才不会那么说话
I don't talk like that.
-我从没...谈过我的胆量 -你怎么回事?
-I never... Talk about my gut. -What is wrong with you?
我没事 只是压力太大
There's nothing wrong with me. I am under a great deal of pressure
我不需要我妻子再给我增加 更多的压力
and I don't need my wife adding more pressure.
你得承认 这女孩很不一样
You have to admit, there is something about this girl.
也许她就是我们前世的守护神
Maybe she was a escort in a past life.
-现在怎么又扯到前世了 -我不知道
-Now we're talking about past lives? -I don't know.
怎么了? 司机哪去了?
What's going on? Where's the driver?
那是他吗?
Is that him?
对 是他 但他这是去哪?
Yeah, that's him. But where's he going?
他好像上出租了
He seems to be getting into a cab.
这是我见过最扯淡的事情 什么...
This is the craziest thing I've ever seen. What...
是我们说错什么了吗
Was it something we said?
必须是啊
Apparently...
要么是我们说错话了 要么是我们 就要被黑帮炸死了
Either that or it's a mob hit and we're about to blow up.
下车 下车
Yeah, well, get out. Get out.
这是什么啊 搞行为艺术的出租司机吗
What is this, like a existential cab driver.
他好像受不了我们拌嘴
I think he couldn't take the tension between us.
可能那就是他的过程
I know, maybe that was his process.
好吧 我就把那该死的角色给她
Okay, I'll give her the goddamn part!
这样就决定了?
That's all it took?
-对 -她欠那司机10美分
-Yeah. -She owes that cabbie ten percent.
喂?
Hello?
珊迪?
Sandy?
你不是开玩笑吧?
You're not kidding, are you?
明天
Tomorrow.
早上10点
10:00 A.M.
好 太感谢了
Okay! Thank you so much!
好 再见
Okay, bye now.
-我得到角色了!  -什么角色?
-I got the part! -What part?
-百老汇!  -百老汇?
-Broadway! -Broadway?
你就是那么得到角色的?
So that's how you got the part?
他是那么告诉我的 对
That's what he told me, yeah.
-你相信了他?  -对
-And you believed him? -Yeah!
这挺有意思的
I think... It's kind of funny,
但我真的想不出来你要怎么 编那么大一个故事
but I really don't see how you can make a story like that up.
就跟你编个名字 或者瞒着妻子搞外遇那样
The same way you make up a name or cheat on your wife.
他骗了你
He lied to you!
我不知道我能不能接受你这说法
I don't know if I agree with you, actually.
因为阿诺德跟我是在一个 非常特别的环境下认识的
Because Arnold and I met under very specific circumstances.
而且他不欠我什么
And he didn't owe me anything.
特别是不欠我真相
Especially not the truth.
他完全没必要把那角色给我
And he certainly didn't have to give me that part.
他肯定也不该给我
And he probably shouldn't have,
这后来给他带来了那么多伤心事
for all the grief that it caused him.
别叫 听我解释
Now, don't yell... Let me explain.
不
Nope!
不 不
No. No.
不 出去
No. Get out!
-我... -不
-I was... -No!
你是我见过最恶劣的人之一
You are one of the most horrible people I've ever met...
不 实际上 你知道吗 你就是我 见过的最恶劣的人
No, in fact, you know what, you are the most horrible person I have ever met.
你推掉我们的晚饭就为了 跟我的病人一起吃饭?
You cancel our dinner to go out with one of my sick patients.
你知不知道这只让我感到 你是多么恶心
Do you know that only tells me how sick you are!
天啊 我只想把这个捅进你的蛋蛋里
God, I just want to shove this up your cock!
珍妮 看在上帝的份上 这都是为了我的戏
Jane, for God's sake, it all has to do with my play.
你的戏?
Your play?
我才不在乎你的什么戏
I don't care about your play!
你愚蠢的戏剧 我也不在乎你
Your stupid little play, I don't care about you.
给我滚
Just get out!
不
No.
-喂?  -你好大的胆子 在我的办公室
-Hello? -How dare you answer your cellphone
接电话!
in my office!
太好了 我真为你感到高兴
That's great! I'm so happy for you.
现在你又开心了
And now you're happy.
现在他开心了 跟我在一起 你总是苦瓜脸 为什么?
Now he's happy. You're always depressed with me. Why is that?
为什么? 那是谁?
Why is that? Who is that?
我现在不方便说话 一会再打给我
I can't talk right now. Call me later.
是那个金发疯婆子吗
Was that the crazy blond?
还是那个饥渴的老爹?
Or the needy father?
珍妮 我必须跟你谈谈
Jane, I must talk to you!
天啊 你知道吗 我看到你们俩就恶心 都给我滚
God, you know what? I'm so sick of both of you. Just get out!
你们俩 滚
All of you, get out!
滚出去
Just get out!
好
Okay.
出去
Out!
真受不了这么紧的衣服
I'm sick of these tight clothes.
我得换身宽松的
I've gotta get a loose-fitting suit or something.
不然就去做个抽脂手术
Either that or it's liposuction.
你身材这么好 得了便宜还卖乖
Come on, you look great. You're fishing for compliments.
-别说啦 -你这乖卖的太大了
-Stop it! -Harpooning is more like it.
嘿 两位陌生人 你们在这干啥呢
Hey, you two strangers, what are you doing here?
我知道你在这干什么
Well, I know what you're doing here.
升职 升职
Promotion, promotion.
-升职了 -嗨
-Promoting. -Hi.
这是切切 我的女公关
This is Cece, my P.R. Lady.
我是西蒙斯小姐 你们能不能 考虑一下帮我们做个广告?
Miss Simmons, would you consider doing a commercial for us?
当然你可以负责导演 西蒙斯先生
And of course you can direct it, Mr. Simmons.
叫我艾伯森就好 谢谢
It's Albertson. Thank you.
-我好像弄错了 -估计是
Well, I guess I blew that one. I guess you did.
谢谢 其实我不接广告
Thank you, but I don't really do commercials.
一向不做
Not my thing.
你要不要去找几件宽松的衣服?
Did you want to find some large clothes?
我只是说别这么紧的
I said less tight...
对 更放松一点或者宽大的衣服在这边
Yeah, but no, the relaxed or the more looser fitting are over here.
很高兴认识你
Nice to meet you.
回头见 赛斯
We'll see you, Seth.
再见 伙计们
See you later, guys.
天啊
My God.
-你急什么呢 -这东西看着就不咋地
-What's the rush? -This stuff doesn't look good,
太贵了 咱们去个好点的地方
and it's too expensive. Let's go some place nice.
香奈儿或者普拉达什么的
Like, like Chanel or Prada.
那儿反而廉价了吗
That's bargain basement.
我感觉我有幽闭恐惧症 在这里快要没法呼吸了
I feel like I'm claustrophobic, I can hardly breathe in here...
-看 我爱花呢 -让我害怕
-Look! I love tweed. -Freaking me out...
我要试试这件
I'm going to try this on.
好 来 我来帮你 我也爱花呢衣服
Okay, here, come on, I'll help you. I love tweed, too.
阿诺德 我不需要你帮忙
Arnold, I don't need your help.
你确定? 来让我看看
Are you sure? Here, let me watch.
等到了家也许你能看我脱掉
At home, maybe you can watch me take it off.
放松点 牛仔
Take it easy, cowboy.
我知道 但我可以看看你 穿上好不好看啊
I know, but I'm a good judge of you in tweed.
我知道 但有时候...
I know, but sometimes it's like...
《爱你就捧你》
Squirrels to the nuts!
你没事吧
Are you okay?
真没想到居然碰到你了 德里克
I cannot believe I'm running into you, Derek!
不 我才不安静
No, I'm not going to be quiet.
我是玛姬 记得吗? 芝加哥的
It's Margie, remember? From Chicago!
我到处找你啊
I've looked everywhere for you.
你不明白 你改变了我的生命
You don't understand, you've changed my life.
我去了时尚学校 我现在是这儿的采购商
I went to fashion school and I'm the executive buyer here...
-除此之外... -别说了
-Besides that... -Shut up...
你给了我这辈子最棒的一晚
You gave me the single best night I've ever had!
在床上床下都是
In bed and out.
都是因为你和《爱你就捧你》
And it's all because of you and the Squirrels To The Nuts!
求你小声点
Please keep your voice down!
好了伙计们 下次见
Okay, see you later, guys.
天啊 赛斯·吉尔伯特
My God, Seth Gilbert!
你们是朋友吗 阿诺德
So, you guys friends, Arnold?
你这说啥呢 赛斯
Where are you going with this, Seth?
你们俩注意点形象 好吗
Now you two behave yourselves, okay?
还有什么你需要的吗?
Is there anything else you need?
《爱你就捧你》 嗯?
"Squirrels To The Nuts,"
你这混蛋 畜生
you weasily, no good son of a bitch!
你别再出现在我面前
Don't you ever, ever speak to me again!
德尔塔 不 德尔塔!
Delta, no! Delta...
赛斯 等等
Seth, wait!
我记下车牌了 肯定能找到
I got the license plate! Easy to trace.
别担心 让我来 我都付钱
No, no, don't worry. I'll take care of it. I'll pay for everything.
她是我老婆 只是赶时间
She's my wife, she was just in a hurry.
对 她有个会要迟到了 而且脑子有点不正常
Yes, she's a little late for a meeting and she's a little scattered-brained.
神经有点大条
Just absent-minded.
布拉德 没事 我认识他 让他处理吧 相信我
Brad, it's okay. I know him. He's good for it. Believe me.
好吧 好吧
Okay, okay.
叫你老婆下次小心点 兄弟
Tell your wife to be more careful, Bub.
我会更小心点
I will... More careful.
听我说 德里克 阿诺德 不管你叫什么
Look, Derek... Arnold... Whatever your name is.
我知道我太大声了 我只是看到你太激动
I know I was speaking too loud. I was just so excited to see you.
-没事 -你要现金 支票还是传票?
-It's okay... -Cash, check or charge?
那女孩干什么的? 站街女?
So what is that girl, a hooker?
就跟你带去尼克饭店那个一样?
Like the one you came to Nick's with?
可能
Could be.
应召女 三陪
Call girl. Escort.
那有什么区别? 反正都是 服务你内裤里那点东西
What's the difference? They all escort you in and out of their pants.
男人啊
Men!
对 你说得对 我们只擅长一件事
Yeah, you're right. We're only good for one thing.
那要不要来一发?
So how about some?
-我在考虑 -我还记得伦敦 德尔塔
-I'm considering it! -I still remember London, Delta.
在那之后我再也没找到过那种感觉
I haven't felt that way since.
得了吧 赛斯
Come on, Seth.
你知道我们都太熟悉 现在已经找不到感觉了
You know we were both too far down other roads for us to get serious.
你才是 我能很快就改变方向
You were. I would've switched direction in a second.
我知道 你已经变了很多方向了
I know. You've switched a bunch of since then.
-对于你就不一样了 -拜托...
-It was different with you. -Come on...
我依然准备好了 德尔
I'm still ready, del.
到地方了 吉尔伯特先生
This is it, Mr. Gilbert.
-这一次你要推销什么?  -我的新古龙水
-What are you promoting this time? -My new cologne.
别告诉我叫什么名字
Don't tell me what it's called.
其实他们想出了一个 非常好的名字
They came up with a pretty good name, actually.
"赛斯的诱惑"
"Seth's Seduction."
很好...
Great...
吉尔伯特先生 你来了真是太好了
Mr. Gilbert, it is so wonderful to have you here!
大家都等不及想见您了
Everybody's been dying to meet you in the flesh.
-你说什么?  -他在戏弄你
-I beg your pardon? -He's teasing you.
-德尔塔 跟上 跟上 -我在努力
-Delta, keep up! Keep up! -I'm trying.
借过
Excuse me.
能给我们签名吗?
Can we have your autograph?
我们已经等了四个 小时了 只耽误你一会儿
We waited four hours in line, it'll only take you a second.
我会赶上你的 我在后面
I'm trying to get to you. I'm behind here.
好的 女士 不能进去了
Okay, lady, the jig's up.
你做什么... 等等 赛斯 赛斯
What are you... Wait! Seth! Seth!
看来她不满意 你想要进去吗?
Well, she ain't a pro. What, you came back for more?
光偷衣服不够吗?
The suit wasn't enough?
不 我不是从这偷的
No, I didn't steal this from here.
-那是从哪偷的?  -不 我根本没偷东西
-Where did you steal it from? -No, I didn't steal it at all.
我在店里和丈夫吵了一场
I got into an argument with my husband at Barney's
然后不知怎么出去了 你应该给他们打电话
and I walked out by accident. You should call them.
他的名字叫阿诺德·艾伯森 现在肯定已经付钱了
His name is Arnold Albertson, I'm sure he's paid for it by now.
能请你们放我下来吗?
Could you please put me down?
好的 女士 我会放你 下来 你是个白痴
All right, lady, I'll put you down. You're an idiot.
我们听过很多说辞 但你这个是最傻的
We hear a lot of stories, but this one tops them all.
"我和丈夫在店里吵架
"I had an argument with my husband at Barney's
所以我来这里 偷另一件衣服"
so I came over to Macy's to steal another suit."
不 你不明白 我根本没偷东西
No, you don't understand. I didn't steal this at all!
喂?
Yes. Hello?
什么? 谁?
What? Who?
警察? 你说什么呢?
The police? What are you talking about?
什么 你疯了吗?  是的 请让她接电话
What, are you crazy? Yes, put her on the phone, please!
阿诺德? 你最好把我弄出去
Arnold? You better get me the hell out of here
然后送我去我父母那
and over to my parents' apartment!
我最好在二十分钟内出去
And I better get there within the next 20 minutes!
你最好确定在我到那里的时候
And you better make damn sure that you're out of the apartment
你已经走了
before I get there!
我建议你自己去 宾馆里开个房间
And what I suggest you do is get yourself a hotel room, buddy,
然后再找一个应召女
and order another call girl!
你真他妈的傻
Squirrels to the fucking nuts!
独角兽 其实是女性的一种象征
The unicorn, you see, was a kind of symbol of women.
这一象征是女人被人像 动物那样对待时候产生的
And this comes from a period when women were treated like Chattel.
像牛那样?
Like Cattle?
不 是动物
No, Chattel.
意思是她们得按照男人 的想法去生活
It basically means they were whatever men wanted them to be.
你是说就像现在的 大多数女性一样?
You mean, like now a lot?
我想是的
Yeah, I guess.
那是我写剧本的原因之一
Part of that's why I wrote the play.
你知道 在很古老的时候 妓女是个神圣的职业
You know, in really ancient times, the prostitute was a sacred profession.
具体是什么时候?
When was this?
在精神和性欲分开之前
Well, before spirituality and sexuality were split apart.
其实不应如此
They really shouldn't be.
是的
Yeah.
你是个很浪漫的人
You're a real romantic guy, aren't you?
我想乔什在我身上 看到了些什么
I guess Josh saw something in me.
和阿诺德不一样
And it wasn't really like Arnold.
你知道 阿诺德和我一样 把钱看得很重
You know, with Arnold, the money was as much for him as it was for me.
但是乔什 我认为他是 第一个相信我的人
But with Josh, I think he was the first person who ever believed in me.
所以自然的 一些过去 认识的人
So, of course, cue somebody from my past
就会出现毁了我的好事
who's going to show up and ruin the whole damn picture.
你为什么让我心碎?
Why are you breaking my heart?
你难道不知道你伤了我的心
Don't you understand you're breaking my heart,
伊莎...戈尔... 不管你叫什么名字
Izzy... Glo... Whatever your name is.
-法官也是有感情的 -先生
-Judges have feelings, too. -Mister!
我不认为我们现在 适合讨论这样的话题
I don't think we're in exactly the best place to have this conversation.
所以我建议你转身 回到你之前的地方去
So I suggest you turn around and go right back where you came from.
我建议你闭上你的嘴
And I suggest that you shut your trap!
我在和这位女士说话...
I am talking to the lady...
这个伤了我心的妓女
The lady of the night over here who broke my heart.
我联系了薇琪的 援交服务 结果第二天...
I call Vickie's escort service and the next day...
-乔什 你做什么?  -爸爸?
-Josh, what are you doing? -Dad?
他是个老年人
He's an old man.
-是的 下流的老头子 -你说的不对
-Yeah, a dirty old man! -That is irrelevant.
好的 好的 有时候下流 但是不老
Okay, okay. Dirty sometimes, but not old!
我的老天 约书亚 你知道 你惹上什么事了吗?
For God's sake, Joshua, do you realize what you're getting yourself into?
这位女士和你的导演 共度过美好一夜
This lady had a night with your director!
我得说是一个很浪漫的夜晚
A perfectly romantic one, I should say.
伊莎贝拉 等等
Isabella! Wait!
伊莎贝拉
Isabella!
乔什知道这件事对于你来说 肯定感觉很难过
It must have been really hard for you, Josh finding out like that.
遭遇到双人包夹 他还有三秒钟时间...
Double team him now, he's got three seconds to get out of...
你去哪了 亲爱的?  一直有人打电话找你
Where ya been honey? The phone's been ringing off the hook for you!
一整天电话都响个不停
All day long! That's too many calls!
-有约书亚...珊迪和阿尔弗雷德 -又来了
-That Joshua... Sandy and Alfred... -Again.
是谁?
What now?
一个叫德里克的
A Derek.
喂?
Hello?
伊莎 我是阿诺德 我想马上见你
Izzy, it's Arnold. I need to see you right away.
你能到巴克利来吗 还是同一个房间 1369号
Can you come over to the barclay, same room. 1369.
我会解释一切 去那见我
I'll explain everything. Just meet me here.
我不知道我是否能去
I don't know if I can do that.
你说那话是什么意思?
What do you mean you don't know if you can do that?
我们得排练 你就赶紧过来吧
We gotta rehearse! Just, just, just get over here.
现在 比赛进入白热化了
Now, they're all five in the ring...
好的
Okay.
你好 薇琪 我是...
Hello, Vickie, this is Dr. Do...
是的 是的 今晚
Yeah. Yeah, tonight.
巴克利酒店 晚上八点 老样子
The barclay. 8:00 P.M. Under the usual name.
你还记得那个姑娘吗?
You remember that girl, Glo stick?
有那样的姑娘吗?
Anyone like that?
这边请 先生
Right this way, sir.
谢谢你 孩子
Thank you, son.
-喂?  -赛斯·奥马利?
-Hello? -Seth O'Malley?
我只是通知你 她已经来了
I'm just confirming she's on her way.
半小时内就会到
She'll be there in half an hour.
很好 谢谢 我在另一个房间
Great, thanks. I'm in a different room.
是的 我知道 你说过...
Yeah, I know. You told me...
等一下 我接个电话
Hang on a minute. I want a description.
好的
Okay.
-什么?  -赛斯?
-Yes? -Seth?
现在怎么样?
How about now?
-德尔塔?  -不 我是示巴女王
-Delta? -No, the Queen of Sheba.
好的 稍等一下 我接一个长途电话 好吗?
Okay, hang on, Sheba. I'm just on the other line. Long distance, okay?
-薇琪?  -她高大 金发
-Vickie? -She's tall and blond and...
阻止她 我现在不能见她
Stop her! I can't see her right now.
阻止他? 我阻止不了 她已经开始了
Stop her? I can't stop her. She's in transit.
-她有手机吗?  -是的
-Has she got a cellphone? -Yeah.
好的 那就打给她叫她 去接待下一个客人
Well, call her and tell her to go on to her next appointment.
也许我之后会联系你
I'll call you later maybe.
我会试试 但是她的手机 有时候不太灵
Well I'll try, but her cellphone hasn't been working so well.
好的 打给她 然后打回给我
Okay, call her and then call me back.
好的
Okay.
-嘿 -什么?
-Hey. -Yes?
好的 过来吧
Well, come on over.
你在哪 在你父母家?  我在1328号房
Where are you, at your parents'? I'm in 1328.
-是的 我马上到 -再见
-Yes, I'll be right there. -See you soon.
抱歉...
Sorry...
没事的
It's okay.
你没接到电话?
Did you not get the call?
你打了给我
You call me.
不 薇琪的电话 她告诉 你叫你去接下个客人
No. Vickie. She called to tell you to go to your next appointment.
我现在很忙
I'm busy now.
很忙? 好的
Busy? Okay.
没事的 我在这等着
It's okay, I will wait for here.
不不不 还有位女士要来
No, no, no, no. Another lady is coming now.
-是的 -好吗?
-Yes. -Yes?
-正好是我爱的人 -明白了
-Who I happen to love. -Yes.
你明白吗?
Do you understand?
我的英语不是很好
My English is not so fast.
天啊
God.
薇琪叫我来这里
Vickie, she tell me come here.
1328号房间
Room 1-3-2-8.
-是吗?  -是的
-Yes? -Yeah.
你不明白
You don't understand.
我还是打给薇琪吧
I call Vickie.
-等等 等等 不不不 -好的
-Wait, wait, wait, no, no, no... -Yes.
等等 别那样 你得离开
Wait, don't do that. You need to go.
是的 打通了
Yes. It's ringing.
天啊...
Jesus Christ...
太乱了
It's all very confusing.
很...乱
And it's... Confusing.
非常
Very.
-你知道 乔什知道我们的事了 -是吗?
-You know, Josh knows about us now. -He does?
赛斯也知道了
So does Seth.
是的 我料到了
Yeah, well... I figured that.
现在只剩下德尔塔了
All that's left is Delta...
你是说我应该继续?
You mean I should stay in the play?
你逗我吗? 当然了 为什么不呢?
Are you kidding? Of course. Why not?
我们是专业的
We're professionals.
不 孔蒂 你现在得 下楼到大厅去
No, Kandi, you have to go back down to the lobby now
在那里打电话 好吗?
and make your call there, okay?
不 薇琪叫我"等等"
No, Vickie, she tell me, "hang on".
我就在这等着
I hang.
该死
Shit!
-是谁?  -是我 赛斯
-Who is it? -It's me, Sethy.
-德尔塔 -是我
-Delta! -Yes.
等等 我穿裤子
Just a second! Pants!
厕所 到厕所去
Bathroom! Get in the bathroom!
我要打给薇琪
I call Vickie.
你马上进去
You get in there now.
好的
Okay...
你觉得他有多少个女人?  为什么他要这样?
How many women do you think he's done this with? Why does he do this?
到底怎么回事?  你知道究竟怎么回事吗?
What is it all about? Do you have any idea what's going on?
这个所谓的"改变我的生活" 计划是什么?
What is this whole "changed my life" business? What is the...
你在说什么呢?
What are you talking about?
我还以为你想谈谈 我们之间的事情
I thought you wanted to talk about us.
回到我们之前的日子和地方....
Go back by the Serpentine and Hyde Park and...
等我一下好吗?
Just hold me for a moment, will you?
过来
Come here.
我依然懂你 德尔
I still got it for you, Del.
亲爱的
Darling,
我要用下你的厕所
let me use your bathroom.
我的什么?
My what?
-你的厕所 -我的厕所
Your bathroom... My bathroom!
马桶坏了
Well, the, the, the toilet's broken.
我得联系他们
I need to call them again.
我不需要马桶
I don't need to use your toilet.
你不需要用马桶
You don't need to use my toilet.
不 我不需要用马桶
No, I don't need to use your toilet.
好的 既然你不需要用 马桶的话...
Well, then I guess if you don't need to use the toilet...
拜托 别再说马桶了
Please, stop saying toilet!
你真奇怪
You are weird.
喂 孔蒂? 孔蒂?
Hello, Kandi? Kandi?
孔蒂 你在听吗?  你现在没事了 你在听吗?
Kandi, is that you? I put you on hold, are you there?
德尔塔...德尔塔 亲爱的 听着 不是你想的那样
Delta... Delta, darling, listen, it's not what you think.
德尔塔
Delta!
德尔塔 德尔塔
Delta! Delta!
1329号房 应该就在 你房间的隔壁
1329, it should be right next door to where you are.
好的 谢谢薇琪
Okay, thanks Vickie.
德尔塔 这是个误会
Delta, it was a misunderstanding.
她不应该来我房间的
She wasn't supposed to come to my room.
拜托 赛斯 你说谎的 功夫比那好的
Come on, Seth. You can do better than that.
既然我知道你要来 为什么还找她 这说不通啊
Why would I have you come over with her? It doesn't make any sense!
那姑娘要用厕所... 她吓坏了 我不明白
The girl needed to use the bathroom... She got scared. I don't know!
女士 是我的错
Lady, it's my fault.
我本来应该去1329号的
I supposed to go 1-3-2-9.
我走错了 感谢你的 厕所 先生
Wrong room. Thanks for bathtub, mister.
-看见了吗? 我说过了 -我还是不相信你
-You see? I told you. -I still don't believe you.
你喜欢你的炮友 跟我丈夫一样
You love your hookers, too. Just like my husband.
不 这是因为我得不到你 而他能得到你
No, it's because I can't have you. He has you.
没人能得到我
Nobody has me.
晚安
Good night.
是的 请接阿诺德·艾伯森的房间
Yes. Arnold Albertson's room, please?
喂?
Hello?
谁? 阿诺德? 是的 是我
Who? Arnold? Yes, this is me.
是谁?
Who is this?
德尔塔 不不
Delta! No, no...
德尔塔 亲爱的 你在哪?
Delta, darling. Where, where, where are you?
楼下 你来这里做什么?
Downstairs? What are you doing here?
我还以为....不不不 是的 我很开心你来了
I thought... No, no, no. Yes, I'm happy to hear from you.
你知道 上次我见你的时候 还在坐牢呢...
You know, the last time I spoke to you you were in jail, and...
是的 直接上来
Yes, come right up.
我的天...
My God...
为什么叫她直接上来?
Why'd you tell her to come up here?
现在是红色警戒 明白我的意思吗?
We're in a code red, do you understand what that means?
一阵暴风坐着电梯上来了
We have a tornado coming up the elevator
很快就要到这里了
and it's about to touch down here.
现在你得离开这 我们得把你...
Now you've got to go. We're gonna put you...
天啊 这里的电梯真他妈快
Jesus, that's the fastest elevator I've ever seen!
厕所
Bathroom!
-我想我会吐的 -安静点
-I think I'm gonna throw up. -Do it quietly.
嗨 亲爱的
Hi, honey.
阿诺德 你这样多久了?
Arnold, how long have you been doing this?
-什么?  -做你正在做的
-Doing what? -Doing what you've been doing.
很明显 你不止做过一次
Obviously, you've done it more than once.
所谓的"松鼠与坚果"
This whole "Squirrels To The Nuts" thing
很明显是你自己的算盘
is obviously your own special little bit.
我还以为这只是 我们的事情 阿诺德
I thought it was just ours, Arnold.
你说这样做是为了 帮助我度过职业生涯的艰难时期
Something you said to help me get through a difficult time in my career.
显然你把这个当做 是你的掩护
Evidently you've been using it as some kind of seduction,
当做是一个诱饵 来引一些人上钩
a kind of lure, a kind of a general serenade for whoever wants to listen.
德尔塔 亲爱的 这个可要比 那个复杂一些
Delta, darling, it's more complicated...
那就看着我的眼睛 告诉我到底怎么回事?
Than meets the eye, yes, I'm sure. Well please, tell me. What is it?
为了你的新作品做研究?
Research for some wonderful new play you're planning?
也许是新的电影?
Some new film, perhaps?
某方面来说是的 我想做一个女性故事
Well, in a way, yes. I'm touched by women's stories.
显然是
Apparently!
不 这是... 我是主张男女平等的
No, it's... I'm sort of a feminist...
是的 当然
Yeah, sure.
那样说也许不对 但是在精神上意识到
That's not the right word, but kind of a mental aware...
你身上的香水味 真奇怪 阿诺德
Odd perfume you're wearing, Arnold.
最近来了一点 "松鼠与坚果"?
Had a little "Squirrels To The Nuts" up here lately?
你说什么呢? 不 我...
What are you talking about? No! I...
我不相信
I don't believe this.
一晚上来两次?
Twice in a night?
德尔塔 德尔塔 德尔塔 不要开门
Delta. Delta. Delta, don't open the door.
德尔塔 不是你想的那样
Delta, it's not what you think it is.
他说的对 你知道 真的不是你想的那样
He's right, you know. It... It's really not.
好的 知道吗?  这一个还更蹩脚
Okay, you know what? This is the Topper!
现在该我走了
And now comes my exit.
离开这里
Out of the room,
离开旅馆
out of the hotel,
告别这戏剧
out of this play,
告别我的生活
out of my life!
祝你们两好运
Good luck to you both!
德尔塔 停下 等等
Delta, stop! Wait!
德尔塔 德尔塔
Delta! Delta!
我不想再听任何话
I don't wanna hear anything more! Ever!
不是看起来的那样
It's not what it looks like!
说实话这不是我第一次 看见伊莎
Well, it's not exactly first time I've seen Izzy leave Arnold's room,
-离开阿诺德的房间 -真有趣
-to be honest, sorry. -How interesting.
看起来所有人都知道怎么回事
It seems that everybody in the entire world knew what was going on
除了我
except for me.
-我真傻 我真傻 -你不傻
-Stupid, stupid me. -You're not stupid.
真高兴看到你们这群人 在危机时刻团结在一起
So glad you boys stick together in a time of crisis.
赛斯 你在这里做什么?  你总是这样
Seth, what are you even doing here? You're always lurking.
你还是跟着你的围巾 和小狗流浪去吧
Just loitering there, with your scarves and your little dog.
不要管这件事
Just stay out of it!
你才是疯子 放着 这么好的妻子不管
You're the lunatic, chasing dames with a wife like this.
看起来男人们都 是喜欢美女的 赛斯
It seems all men like chasing dames, Seth.
不 西蒙斯太太 他只是试着帮忙
No, miss Simmons, he was just trying to help.
你知道 他改变了我的生活 他给了我三万美金
You know, he changed my life. He gave me $30,000
今天我有了我的 第一间公寓
and today I got my first apartment.
-他做了什么?  -三万美金?
-He what? -Thirty thousand dollars? U.S.?
-是的 -我再也受不了了
-Yeah. -I can't handle any more!
一晚上三万美金?  你的功夫肯定挺好
For one night? You must be good.
不不不 你不明白
No, no, no, you don't understand...
我只是试着...
I was trying...
你高兴了?
You happy?
你怎么能这样武断
Where do you get the right to be so judgmental!
听着 伙计 你不会想和我 打的 我能揍扁你
Listen, mate! You don't want to fight me, I'll kick the shit out of you!
-我是受过伦敦街头训练的 -是吗?
-Trained on the streets of London! -Really?
你说的伦敦是七年前 勾引我妻子的伦敦吗?
Is that the same London where you seduced my wife, seven years ago?
根本不是那么回事 她爱的是你
Nothing of the sort at all. She loved you!
我都不知道为什么
Not that I can see why or how!
为什么? 也许是因为 我是好人 而且我喜欢...
Why? Maybe because I'm a good guy and I like...
-喜欢妓女 -是的 没错
-Who likes hookers! -Yeah. Checkmate!
因为我不完美 知道吗?  但你也一样
Because I'm not perfect, okay? Neither are you!
天啊 这是浪费时间 这是浪费时间
Jesus Christ, this is a waste of time. It's a waste of time!
我要去睡觉了 好吗?
I'm going to go to sleep now, okay?
困了 困了
Tired! Tired!
我只能说在早上
All I can say is that in the morning
和你一起合作还是很愉快的
it's going to be a distinct pleasure working with you, Arnold.
-是的 你的房间在这边 -我知道
-Yeah. Your room's over here! -I knew that!
有些时候的夜晚当你回到家
There were those nights when you get home
没人好联系
and there's no one to call.
没有剩下的酒可以喝
And there's no vodka left to drink.
除了一些商业广告外 也没什么好看的节目
And you got nothing on TV apart from those stupid infomercials.
你就一个人呆着
And you're stuck with yourself.
那就是人们所说的恐怖的意思
And that's what they mean when they say the word terror.
因为我只想沉浸在 某个人的怀抱里
Because all I wanted was to be wrapped up in somebody's arms.
任何人的怀抱里
Anybody's arms.
即使是陌生人也行
Even a stranger's.
我讨厌孤独
I hate... I hate being alone.
但是当我孤独的时候 我会看着镜子
But when I am, I look into the mirror
然后跟我自己说 奥黛丽·赫本说过的话
and I tell myself something that Audrey Hepburn once said...
"我相信粉红色
"I believe in pink.
我相信微笑是最好 的减肥方式
"I believe that laughter is the best calorie burner.
我相信吻
"I believe in kissing.
经常吻
"Kissing a lot.
我相信坚强
"I believe in being strong
即使周围的一切看来不对
"even when everything around you seems to be going wrong.
我相信快乐的女孩 是最美的
"I believe that happy girls are the prettiest girls.
我相信明天是新的一天
"And I believe that tomorrow is another day.
我相信奇迹"
And I believe in miracles!"
我相信奇迹
I believe in miracles.
你知道 那是...
You know, that...
那办法每次都有用
That works every single time.
嘿 伊莎贝拉 谢天谢地
Hey, Isabella. Thank God.
我昨晚一直打你的电话 但是你没接
I was trying to call you all night last night, you didn't pick up your phone.
我真的不知道该做什么
I didn't really know what to do.
你知道 我想我只是来这里
You know, I figured I'd just show up.
-早上好 乔什 伊莎 -嘿
-Morning Josh. Izzy. -Hey.
-睡得怎么样 亲爱的?  -不好
-How did you sleep, darling? -Not good.
不要让它影响你
Don't let it get ya down!
好的 我们开始吧 今天不能浪费时间
Okay, let's start right in. We don't want to waste any time today.
人都到齐了吗?
Is everybody here?
是的 除了德尔塔都到了
Yeah, everybody but Delta.
那就不是到齐了
Well, then, everybody's not here!
你说除了德尔塔都 到齐了是什么意思?
What do you mean, "Yeah, everybody but Delta?"
你应该说"除了德尔塔都来了"
You mean, "Everybody but Delta", you leave out the "Yeah."
除了德尔塔都来了 先生
Everybody's here but Delta, sir.
好的 别叫我先生 珊迪
Okay, don't call me sir, Sandy.
好的 我们就先开始吧
All right, we're going to start without her.
我们先坐下读剧本吧
Let's just sit down and have a table-read.
大家早上好
Good morning, everybody!
我想我们先读剧本吧
I assume we're starting with a reading.
是的 我正要说这个
Yes, that's what I was just saying.
-我想也许我们可以坐下来... -好的
-I thought maybe we'd just sit down... -Fine!
我们开始之前先 讲些事情
Let me just say something here before we get started.
听着 我们都是专业人员
Look, we're all professionals here.
但那并不意味着我们的 私生活就没问题
Which isn't to say that we don't have problems in our private lives
当然偶尔会有问题
from time to time. Of course we do.
但是我们之所以专业 就是因为我们不会让这些问题
But what makes us professionals is that we don't let those problems
干涉我们的工作
slop over into our work.
我们不在工作的时候 谈论那些问题
And we can't talk about them in any way, shape or form.
把它加入到你的表演中 成为催化剂
Use it for your performance, let it fuel that,
但是可不能被它们分心了
But don't let it distract you from our purpose here.
当然这样的一套陈词滥调
Which is, of course, that old show business cliche,
是我深信不疑的
which I happen to really believe in.
表演必须继续
The show must go on and it will!
-我们要让公众看到 -好的
-We owe it to the public. -Fine!
我很同意你的看法
I agree with you absolutely,
但是我没有看剧本
but I'd just as soon not read the play.
我想从第一幕第一场开始
I would like to begin with act 1 scene 1,
就是赛斯和我的对手戏 我想马上开演
between Seth's character and mine. I'd like to get it up right away.
-等等 你说什么?  -你听到了
-Wait, I beg your pardon? -On its feet.
好的...
Okay...
是的 我想我们应该 先把剧本全看一遍
Yeah, well, I think that we should read the entire play first...
考虑到现在的情况
Well, considering the situation,
当然我们不想谈
which of course we're not going to speak about,
我想我们应该帮助 演员们适应它们
I think we ought to just help the actors get through this,
就像进入到一个 漫长黑暗隧道的尽头
like getting to the end of a long, dark tunnel,
而不是去盲目的遵循 一些已于的规则
rather than try to follow some accepted directorial rules.
我认为你是一个 非常有创新的导演
I'd like to think you're bigger than that as a director.
有人有问题吗? 赛斯? 伊莎?
Anybody have a problem with this? Seth? Izzy?
-有问题吗?  -没有
-Anybody? -Nope.
-不 我没有 -很好
-No, not me. -Great!
好的 我们从第一场开始 只需要赛斯和德尔塔
Okay we'll start with scene 1. Only Seth and Delta are needed.
其他人可以看剧本
The rest of us can watch from the orchestra.
在卧室里安排一张 沙发和两把椅子行吗?
Would you bring out the bedroom with the couch and the two chairs?
好的 幕布升起来
All right, the curtain rises.
在哈尔·芬尼根旅馆的房间里
It's hal finnegan's hotel suite.
德尔塔 准备好了就说...
Delta, whenever you're ready...
第一句话不是我说的 如果是我就开始了
Well, I don't have the first line. But if I did I would begin.
好的
All right.
"既然你不想理解 我说的话 我能说什么呢?
"Well, you refuse to understand what I'm saying, so what can I say?
我想我很抱歉"
I'm sorry, I guess."
"没事的 我习惯了
"That's okay, I'm used to it.
你在不知道自己在说 什么时总是大喊大叫"
You always yell when you don't know what you're talking about."
"我知道我在说什么 只是你不想听
"I know what I'm talking about, you don't want to hear it.
这事情真是娘气"
It's a real female thing."
"当你不想听的时候 你就不去听"
"When you don't want to hear something, you just don't hear it."
"我真的很难理解你是
"Well, it's very hard for me to understand
如何做到和别的女人 睡觉之后再和我睡的
"how you can sleep with other women and then sleep with me
然后告诉我没有任何关系"
and tell me it doesn't mean anything."
-这是真的 -所以你说
-"Well, it's true." -"So you're saying
"你和别的女人共度的时间
"that the time you spend with other women
都只是逢场作戏
"doesn't exist any more in your brain.
那不应该是很美好的回忆吗? "
It isn't some sort of pleasant memory?"
不 我没那么说
"No, I didn't say that."
-那好吧 -什么?
-"Well, then..." -"Well, then what?"
"当你和我做爱的时候
"How can I not think about what you're thinking about
我怎么才能不去想 你在想的事情? "
"when you're making love to me?
"我怎么知道你当时 想的是我
"How do I know you're with me and not with some other woman
而不是别的女人呢? "
"you made love to some other time?
所以我们不同步
"Therefore we're not in sync?
因为也许我也在想 别的男人 对吧?
Because I might be thinking about some guy, too, right?"
我不知道我们怎么会这样
"I don't know how we got here.
我只是说了句"我们为何不去 素食餐厅
"All I said was, 'why don't we go to a vegetarian restaurant.'
然后这吵闹就爆发了
"And this had to happen."
把它给我
"Give me that."
-不 你戒了 -你也是
-"No, you quit." -"So did you."
我破了戒并不意味着 我就得...
"Well, just because I'm breaking my thing, doesn't mean I..."
干嘛 我连抽口烟都不行?
"What... I can't have a puff on your cigarette?"
-我没那么说 -那你就给我啊
-"I didn't say that." -"Well, then, give it to me."
不 现在抽烟让我觉得不好
"No, I feel bad now for smoking.
因为这让我觉得 我怂恿你破戒了
'Cause it's like I'm breaking your thing..."
我有自己的独立思想 我现在就想抽支烟
"I have an independent mind. I want a fucking puff on the cigarette! Now!"
-好的 给你 -谢谢你
-"Okay, here." -"Thank you."
叮铃铃...
Ring-Ring! Ring-Ring!
干嘛不接电话?
"Why don't you answer it?
也许是你朋友打来的
"It's probably one of your friends.
反正我朋友从来不打电话
"None of my friends can ever get through."
你自己去接 我现在 不想和任何人说话
"Answer it yourself. I've no interest in talking to anybody right now."
我有点饿了
"I'm getting kinda hungry...
你想做什么?
"What do you want to do?"
我要你过来吻我
"I want you to come over here and kiss me."
有详细的要求吗?
"Any particular way?"
蒙住眼睛 我双腿交叉
"Blindfolded with my legs crossed."
不如我蒙住眼睛 亲你的腿如何?
"How about blindfolded with your legs apart?"
这台词我觉得不太好 乔什 你觉得呢?
I'm not sure about that line, Josh. What do you think?
读剧本就好 赛斯
Just read the fucking script, Seth.
好的 好的 好的
Okay. Okay. Okay.
之后再回答你的傻问题
We'll get to your dumb actor questions later.
按照剧本读 赛斯
Just read it, Seth.
不如蒙住眼睛 你双腿分开?
"How about blindfolded with your legs apart?"
闭上嘴吻我
"Just shut up and kiss me."
他 他倾下身子 给她一个深吻
"He, he, he leans in and gives her a long kiss."
好的...
Okay...
好的 好的 我明白了
All right, okay. I got it!
嘿 够了 停下
Hey, that's it! Cut!
怎么了 卡里古拉?  要我坐在这里看这个?
What is this, caligula? I'm suppose to sit here and watch this?
抱歉 我入戏太深
Sorry, I got really into it.
拜托 够了 我们来第十场
Come on, that's it. We're going to take ten.
她不错
She's good.
-谢普 怎么了?  -黑尔
-Shep! What's going on? -Heel!
黑尔
Heel.
你在这做什么? 珍妮在哪?
What are you doing here? Where's Jane?
什么? 威尔巴
What? Wilba!
-威尔巴 回来 -这是怎么回事?
-Wilba, come back! -What the hell is going on here?
我来告诉你怎么回事
I'll tell you what's going on here.
你雇佣那个妓女 因为她很有技巧
You hired that hooker because she turns good tricks.
好的 你喜欢那些技巧吗?
Well, would you like some good tricks?
因为我会很多 谁想先来的?
'Cause I got a bag full of them. Who wants to go first?
我能让你们都满足
I've got tricks on all of you!
珍妮 你这样很没礼貌 非常不专业
Jane, this is very inappropriate and unprofessional!
我才不管你想什么
I don't give a shit what you think!
你以为你是谁 海明威吗?
Who do you think you are, Hemingway?
珍妮·克莱蒙特小姐
Miss Jane Claremont,
你没有任何权利 谈论你的病人
you have absolutely no right to be talking about your patients
不管用什么方式
in any way, shape or form!
你是谁?
And you are?
爸爸 你穿着那衣服做什么?
Dad! What are you doing in that outfit?
-我的天啊 -那是你父亲?
-My goodness. -That's your father?
那个经常找你的人是个拉比?
The man who calls you constantly... Is a rabbi?
拜托 我们现在在彩排
Come on, we're in the middle of a God damn rehearsal!
-是的 -根据我的观察
-Yeah. -Well, from what I've just observed,
我想你就要失去你的妻子了
I think you might be in the middle of losing your wife!
这个人是谁?
Who is this person?
她是谁 阿诺德?
Who is she, Arnold?
我不知道
I have no idea!
她是我的前女友 阿诺德
She's my ex-girlfriend, Arnold.
我是了解这一切的人
I am the person that knows what's going on here
而且我受够了
and I'm fed up with it.
这个女人被雇来和这里 的很多人上了床
This woman has been hired to sleep with a number of people in this room.
我已经知道了两个 现在也许有三个了吧?
Two that I know of, by now probably three?
真的吗?
Really?
那么我就应该把
Then I'm going to beat the shit out of anybody
和我女儿睡了觉的人 打出屎来
who paid to sleep with my daughter.
是谁?
Who was it?
有他
It was him.
-他...和他 -那是谎话
-Him... And him. -That's a lie!
子弹可以杀人 但是拳头 可以把事情闹大
A bullet can kill, but a punch can change things for the living.
我给你举个例子
I'll give you spoilers.
约翰·韦恩和伦道夫·斯科特
John Wayne and Randolph Scott tore
为了马琳·黛德丽在酒吧 大打出手
apart a bar fighting for Marlene Dietrich.
当然约翰·韦恩赢了 然后他们幸福的生活着
John Wayne won, of course, and they lived happily ever after.
我们从没做
We never did it.
住手 阿尔 住手 你以为你在做什么?
Stop it, Al, just stop it! What the hell do you think you're doing?
这只是一场戏剧
This is all just a play!
这个又是谁?
And who... Who is this?
我父亲打破了僵局
My father tore a hole in the sky.
大家都松了一口气
Everyone felt a release.
慢点 先生
Slow down, sir.
你不能就这样进来然后 把一切都毁了
You can't just come in here and ruin everything I'm doing, dad.
怎么回事?
What is going on?
不要靠近我
Don't come towards me!
别过来 不然我会吹哨子
Don't come, I'll blow this whistle again!
如果你不放开过去 未来就会受到影响
If you don't let go of your past, it'll strangle your future.
这是...给我一点
What is... Give me those!
那些不是玩具
Those are not playthings.
不 是橡胶做的
No, they're rubbers.
说橡胶不太好 亲爱的
It's not nice to say rubbers, darling.
-不 他们是避孕套 -不 是橡胶
-No, they're condoms. -No, they're rubbers.
很高兴担任了这个角色
Wonderful plays your father directs...
不 它们就是避孕套
No, they're condoms.
我要离开我的生活
I'm going to live my life!
再见了
So long!
什么? 什么?
What? What?
那是我们的孩子
There's our baby!
-我们的孩子 -嘿 她是我的
-Our baby! -Hey! She's mine.
精彩 精彩
Bravo! Bravo!
精彩
Bravo!
评论怎么样 好吗?
So the plays' reviews were that good?
好像演了一周
I thought it closed in a week?
是的...
Yeah...
我是说 问题是 长岛的妻子们
I mean, the problem is, Long Island house wives,
她们可不愿意去看 一群应召女演话剧
they don't want to spend their big night out in the company of call girls.
她们想看跳舞的狮子
They want dancing lions.
她们想看唱歌
They want singing mormons, you know.
她们去影院是为了逃避
They go to the theater to escape.
很讽刺 对吧?
It's ironic, isn't it?
但是还有些魔法在等着我
But there was still a sprinkle of magic waiting for me.
观众席中在我妈妈 身后坐着一个人
There was this guy in the audience, sat behind my mother,
他拥有一家电影工作室
and he owned a movie studio.
剩下的就是历史了
And the rest is history.
是的 我很幸运
Yeah, well, I was really lucky.
就是那个导致了你和 乔什的分开吗?
Is that what caused you and Josh to split up?
你成功了?
Your success?
你知道 我只是觉得生活中
Well, you know, I just feel like some things in life
有些事情是无法永远持续的
aren't meant to last forever.
嘿 赛斯
Hey, Seth!
-嘿 薇琪 -抱歉来迟了
-Hey, Vickie. -Sorry we're late.
-没关系 -她是谁?
-That's okay. -Who's that?
她为什么在这儿?  那些女人是谁?
Why is she here? Who are all those women?
你邀请了她们吗?  她们是应召女?
Did you invite them? Is this an activist group?
可以那么说
You could say that.
-天啊 不 趴下 -什么?
-Dear God, no! Get down! -What?
-我的脚很疼 -我的天
-My feet are killing me. -My God...
-松鼠和坚果 -不不不
-Squirrels to the nuts! -No, no, no...
他就是我经常说起的家伙
That's the guy I always talked to you about!
-我还以为事情结束了 -是啊
-I thought that was the end. -It is!
你不知道.... 你不知道你改变了我的生活
You have no idea... You have no idea! You changed my life!
我找了所有叫迈克尔·哈里森的人
I looked for every Michael Harrington in the world, practically.
我用那些钱发展了 镇上最好的三陪服务
I took that money and parlayed it into the best escort service in town, honey.
你觉得她们如何?
How do you like them apples?
见到你真好
Great to see you!
再见 回见
Bye, I'll catch you later.
结束了
That's the end.
阿诺德怎么样了?
And Arnold?
我没见到他
Well, I haven't seen him.
最近听说他在为 非营利性组织工作
Last I heard he was working for some sort of non-profit organization
为女性慈善机构 捐赠了不少钱
making very large, anonymous donations to women's charities.
然后德尔塔看上了新的人
And then Delta, she fell for a new guy.
一个火箭专家 她想上月球
Some sort of rocket scientist. You know, she's over the moon about that.
而我的医生...我想依然 和赛斯·吉尔伯特在一起
And then my therapist... I think she's still with Seth Gilbert.
你知道 红色蜜蜂
You know, the red bees. So...
发展的非常好
Yeah, it all wrapped up real nice.
就像是一部电影
You know, sort of just like a movie.
那你呢? 你找到另一半了吗?
What about you? Is there a person in your life?
我找到了一个良师益友
Well, let's just say I got a mentor...
其实就是因为他 我才告诉你这些
He's actually a lot of the reason why I'm telling you all this.
他是一个很会讲道理的人
He's very into saying it how it is.
他说这个镇子的人 喜欢有过去的演员
He says that this town loves an actress with a past
他说的很对
and he's sure right about that.
听起来你找到了自己的位置
Well, it sounds like you've found your place.
不管是什么 你都很开心
Wherever you are, that's your happy place.
就像松鼠和坚果
Squirrels to the nuts, and all of that.
你现在会引用了?
You're quoting cluny brown now?
什么?
What?
那句台词是克鲁尼·布朗说的
That "Squirrels To The Nuts" line, it's from Lubitsch's Cluny Brown.
-嘿 亲爱的 -嘿
-Hey, darling. -Hey.
是查尔斯·博野 对詹妮弗·琼斯说过的
It's what Charles Boyer says to Jennifer Jones
在他们相爱之前
just before they fall in love.
你是在告诉我这句话 甚至不是原创吗?
You mean to tell me after all that, it's not even original?
什么原创?
What's original?
亲爱的 如果我们还想 去看演唱会的话
Honey, if we're going to get to the Sonny Chiba triple feature
现在就得走了
we need to leave right now.
他是个功夫明星
He's a kung-fu actor.
他是这个地球上 唯一比我还爱电影的人
He's the only guy on the planet who loves movies more than I do.
是的 但是你知道很多
Yep. True! But you know a lot.
真有趣
That's very interesting,
你看起来很压抑
you don't seem to be inhibited.
试着特别一些
Try to be more specific,
是什么让你觉得不合适?
what made you think that you were out of place?
我没这么想
I didn't think I was.
是阿尔叔叔 他总是告诉我
It's Uncle Arn. He's always telling me,
"克鲁尼·布朗 你不知道你的位置"
"Cluny Brown, you don't know your place."
没人能决定你的位置
Nobody can tell you where your place is.
我的位置是什么?  大家的位置是什么?
Where is my place? Where is anybody's place?
我告诉你是什么
I'll tell you where it is.
你开心的地方就是你的位置
Wherever you're happy, that's your place.
开心是让人适应环境
And happiness is a matter of purely personal adjustment
最好的方式
to your environment.
比如说在海德公园
In Hyde Park, for instance.
有些人喜欢给松鼠喂坚果
Some people like to feed nuts to the squirrels.
但是如果你觉得给 坚果喂松鼠很有趣
But if it makes you happy to feed Squirrels To The Nuts,
那就可以去做 没什么不对的
who am I to say nuts to the squirrels?
你做了什么 笨蛋?
What did you do? Schmuck!
谢谢你 埃利奥特
Thank you, Elliot.
你要考虑的就是
All you could come up with
所谓职业道德的软肋
was this weak borscht about professional ethics
因为你担心人们是否 能处理好这些冠冕堂皇
because you are worried about how this thug will handle rejection.